[
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I wanted to be a government employee but due to the financial problem of my family I could not wait for government job exam and now I am school teacher. I want to know is it like, Allah wanted me to be a teacher that\u2019s why I am a teacher? Or if I could try for a better job my destiny could have been changed?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Whatever you get in this life has already been predestined and written down 50 thousand years before the creation of the heavens and earth! There is no point in thinking of how things would have been had you done this or that as this is one the biggest traps of satan! Be content of what you have and if there is a chance to improve it, go ahead with it.",
    "tags": ["Divine Will and Decree"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-wanted-to-be-a-government-employee-but-due-to-the-financial-problem-of-my-family-i-could-not-wait-for-government-job-exam-and-now-i-am-school-teacher-i-want-to-know-is-it-like-allah-want/",
    "date": "May 28, 2024 10:59 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I wanted to be a government employee but due to the financial problem of my family I could not wait for government job exam and now I am school teacher. I want to know is it like, Allah wanted me to be a teacher that\u2019s why I am a teacher? Or if I could try for a better job my destiny could have been changed?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Whatever you get in this life has already been predestined and written down 50 thousand years before the creation of the heavens and earth! There is no point in thinking of how things would have been had you done this or that as this is one the biggest traps of satan! Be content of what you have and if there is a chance to improve it, go ahead with it.",
    "tags": ["Divine Will and Decree"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-wanted-to-be-a-government-employee-but-due-to-the-financial-problem-of-my-family-i-could-not-wait-for-government-job-exam-and-now-i-am-school-teacher-i-want-to-know-is-it-like-allah-want/",
    "date": "May 28, 2024 10:59 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it permissible to look at the pictures of women who are covering their awrah?or I can\u2019t look at them even if they are covered?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is totally prohibited as Allah ordered you to lower your gaze from non mahrams!",
    "tags": ["Character and Morals"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-permissible-to-look-at-the-pictures-of-women-who-are-covering-their-awrahor-i-cant-look-at-them-even-if-they-are-covered/",
    "date": "May 26, 2024 4:24 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I discussed my mehr with my husband prior to my nikah, and I included a condition along with the sum he was paying. He agreed and promised to provide me anything I asked for in the future within his boundaries, so I took his word on it. However, since we kept it between us, and it wasn\u2019t recorded in writing, is it still valid? What if he denies that now?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not how mahr is decided You both must agree to an amount for mahr and it cannot be ambiguous like this. Also the witnesses must testify such conditions.",
    "tags": ["Dowry"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-discussed-my-mehr-with-my-husband-prior-to-my-nikah-and-i-included-a-condition-along-with-the-sum-he-was-paying-he-agreed-and-promised-to-provide-me-anything-i-asked-for-in-the-future-wi/",
    "date": "May 23, 2024 9:34 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is the Salaah valid if it is prayed inside a bedroom that contains an ensuite? An ensuite is a toilet inside the actual bedroom but it is separated from the rest of the bedroom by walls and a door (basically a room inside another room). Does the door need to be closed during the Salaah?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in praying in such a room even if the toilet door is not closed.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-the-salaah-valid-if-it-is-prayed-inside-a-bedroom-that-contains-an-ensuite-an-ensuite-is-a-toilet-inside-the-actual-bedroom-but-it-is-separated-from-the-rest-of-the-bedroom-by-walls-and/",
    "date": "May 20, 2024 9:07 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh can we go to washroom during azan some people say we cant",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in this whatsoever! What people are saying is baseless and has nothing to do with Islam.",
    "tags": ["Innovations", "Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-can-we-go-to-washroom-during-azan-some-people-say-we-cant/",
    "date": "May 17, 2024 3:28 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Placing phone in front of you while praying is it permissible or should we keep it in our pockets ..is that both permissible",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Both are permissible as long as you don\u2019t get distracted by that",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-placing-phone-in-front-of-you-while-praying-is-it-permissible-or-should-we-keep-it-in-our-pockets-is-that-both-permissible/",
    "date": "May 14, 2024 2:40 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: What is the minimum age for giving zakat",
    "answer": "ANSWER: There is no such age. Zakat if given on the wealth, regardless whether it is owned by an orphan child or someone insane",
    "tags": ["Zakat"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-what-is-the-minimum-age-for-giving-zakat/",
    "date": "May 10, 2024 9:46 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: In my community, many people use rude words. Thankfully, I don\u2019t use them, but since I\u2019m surrounded by it, I hear those words often. Sometimes, they get stuck in my head, and I accidentally think or almost say them. Am I sinful for that? and What should I do about\u00a0this\u00a0situation?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You must surround yourself with practicing brothers all the time who don\u2019t use profanity. Whatever goes through your mind is forgiven as long as you don\u2019t say it verbally nor act upon it.",
    "tags": ["Character and Morals", "Etiquette, Morals and Heart-Softeners"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-in-my-community-many-people-use-rude-words-thankfully-i-dont-use-them-but-since-im-surrounded-by-it-i-hear-those-words-often-sometimes-they-get-stuck-in-my-head-and-i-accidentall/",
    "date": "May 7, 2024 2:51 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is there a specific duaa I could make for increase in beauty?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No.",
    "tags": ["Beautification & Cosmetic Suregry", "Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-there-a-specific-duaa-i-could-make-for-increase-in-beauty/",
    "date": "May 3, 2024 7:19 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If I\u2019m outside and don\u2019t have any way to perform wudhu, then can I pray the fard salah of that waqt without wudhu?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not permissible as you must perform wudhu if there is water even if you do it underneath the abayah",
    "tags": ["Ablution (Wudhu)"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-im-outside-and-dont-have-any-way-to-perform-wudhu-then-can-i-pray-the-fard-salah-of-that-waqt-without-wudhu/",
    "date": "April 29, 2024 4:26 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: It is a requirement to uncover your head for passport photo in visa process for the UK. My sister went there for study and she did that. Is this ok if this a requiremnt or we should just not do that?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If there is a necessity, this is permissible. A necessity is defined in Islam as something you need to do to ward off harm or death as in the case of eating dead meat or pork when someone is stranded and about to die out of hunger and this is the only option for him.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Women clothing"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-it-is-a-requirement-to-uncover-your-head-for-passport-photo-in-visa-process-for-the-uk-my-sister-went-there-for-study-and-she-did-that-is-this-ok-if-this-a-requiremnt-or-we-should-just-not/",
    "date": "April 25, 2024 4:29 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: In country that I live in, government don\u2019t allow beard in school\u2019s and they want to make my mother pay fine, what should I do?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Pay the fine or quit the school and go for homeschooling.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Men Clothing"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-in-country-that-i-live-in-government-dont-allow-beard-in-schools-and-they-want-to-make-my-mother-pay-fine-what-should-i-do/",
    "date": "April 21, 2024 4:16 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: In my culture, the people on Eid day greet each other with a hug three times and they do not really do this outside of Eid day (occasionally they may). Someone told me that because the people single out Eid day to do this hug, it becomes a bid\u2019ah (innovation) and we should not do it. I want to know if this is bid\u2019ah and whether or not I should stop people from giving me this triple hug on Eid.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in this (between same gender and mehrams) as its a cultural thing and people do not do it as an act of worship.",
    "tags": ["Innovations", "Sports, Entertainment and Music"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-in-my-culture-the-people-on-eid-day-greet-each-other-with-a-hug-three-times-and-they-do-not-really-do-this-outside-of-eid-day-occasionally-they-may-someone-told-me-that-because-the-peopl/",
    "date": "April 18, 2024 3:37 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it permissible to fill a gap in the row in congregation if by doing so we would walk infront of a praying person?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Yes, as the imam is the sutra for the followers if this praying person is praying in the congregation. But if he is praying his sunnah prayer, this is not permissible.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-permissible-to-fill-a-gap-in-the-row-in-congregation-if-by-doing-so-we-would-walk-infront-of-a-praying-person/",
    "date": "April 15, 2024 3:26 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it accurate to say that if an individual engages in backbiting, they will not be forgiven on the Night of Laylatul Qadar unless they seek forgiveness from the person they spoke against?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Backbiting is not related to laylatul qadr being accepted or rejected. Asking people for forgiveness might cause more harm.",
    "tags": ["Fasting and Ramadan", "Taraweeh, Tahajjud and Qiyam-ul-Layl"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-accurate-to-say-that-if-an-individual-engages-in-backbiting-they-will-not-be-forgiven-on-the-night-of-laylatul-qadar-unless-they-seek-forgiveness-from-the-person-they-spoke-against/",
    "date": "April 7, 2024 6:50 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Can I pray tahajjud on days when I missed my Isha Fardh prayer?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If you missed it due to menses and were clean after midnight, you can offer tahajjud without a problem.",
    "tags": ["Taraweeh, Tahajjud and Qiyam-ul-Layl"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-can-i-pray-tahajjud-on-days-when-i-missed-my-isha-fardh-prayer/",
    "date": "March 31, 2024 5:08 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: What should a woman do if she has not kept her skipped fasts(due to menstruation) after Ramadan, eversince her puberty? Does she have to keep all the skipped fasts of past 18 years? Or feed the poors? If to feed, then how many?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: There is no expiation for this except to repent to Allah while showing deep remorse and to keep all those missed fasts of the past.",
    "tags": [
      "Fasting",
      "Fasting and Ramadan",
      "Menstruation and post-natal bleeding"
    ],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-what-should-a-woman-do-if-she-has-not-kept-her-skipped-fastsdue-to-menstruation-after-ramadan-eversince-her-puberty-does-she-have-to-keep-all-the-skipped-fasts-of-past-18-years-or-feed/",
    "date": "March 26, 2024 6:39 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: After coming to masjid for friday prayer. I pray 2 rakat tahiyatul masjid then sit. The imam gives the sermon in our language at the beginning. After finishing it, he gives us some time to pray and I pray 2rakat nafl. Then after like 10 min the adhan is given and he gives sermon in arabic in the mimbar. Is my prayer according to sunnah?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: There are no Sunnah prayers before Friday prayer except the two rakahs of Tahiyatul Masjid that you must pray before sitting down and the general voluntary nafl that is not restricted to a particular number until the Imam comes out.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-after-coming-to-masjid-for-friday-prayer-i-pray-2-rakat-tahiyatul-masjid-then-sit-the-imam-gives-the-sermon-in-our-language-at-the-beginning-after-finishing-it-he-gives-us-some-time-to-p/",
    "date": "March 21, 2024 4:33 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it permissible to open the Qur\u2019an and listen to the recitation during Taraweeh while looking at it?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It is not permissible for the follower to do so. They should listen to the imam without distracting others next to them and must put the right hand over the left and to look at the spot of prostration.",
    "tags": ["Taraweeh, Tahajjud and Qiyam-ul-Layl"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-permissible-to-open-the-quran-and-listen-to-the-recitation-during-taraweeh-while-looking-at-it/",
    "date": "March 17, 2024 4:40 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it permissible to skip fast as I\u2019m travelling to my hometown and also I\u2019m meeting my wife after 6 months, so we might be intimate and that could break the fast.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: When going back to your hometown, you can skip fasting while you are on the road traveling. If you reach your hometown in the morning and you are not fasting, you can not be intimate with your wife who is fasting and must wait.",
    "tags": ["Fasting", "Fasting and Ramadan"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-permissible-to-skip-fast-as-im-travelling-to-my-hometown-and-also-im-meeting-my-wife-after-6-months-so-we-might-be-intimate-and-that-could-break-the-fast/",
    "date": "March 15, 2024 4:46 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Once my mother became extremely sad and cried. While crying about many of her sorrows, she said \u201cWhy Allah gave me life like this\u201d. Is this kufr?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is one of the major sins and can easily lead to major kufr depending on the level of objection and rejection to Allah\u2019s divine decree",
    "tags": ["Apostasy"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-once-my-mother-became-extremely-sad-and-cried-while-crying-about-many-of-her-sorrows-she-said-why-allah-gave-me-life-like-this-is-this-kufr/",
    "date": "March 12, 2024 1:17 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it necessary for a woman to wear a scarf on her head during Azaan? Will it be a sin if we don\u2019t take it?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is an innovation.",
    "tags": ["Innovations", "Women clothing"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-necessary-for-a-woman-to-wear-a-scarf-on-her-head-during-azaan-will-it-be-a-sin-if-we-dont-take-it/",
    "date": "March 10, 2024 3:46 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Can we sacrifice 2 goats for male child as akikah but in Two different places? For example one in our home country and one in the country we are living in?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem.",
    "tags": ["Slaughtering"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-can-we-sacrifice-2-goats-for-male-child-as-akikah-but-in-two-different-places-for-example-one-in-our-home-country-and-one-in-the-country-we-are-living-in/",
    "date": "March 7, 2024 2:54 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I have a problem when I am sleeping sometimes I have a wet dream and ghusl becomes fared on me. but the time that I woke up was right before sunrise or a couple of minutes before. What should I do in this situation if I don\u2019t have enough time to do ghusl or wudu?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You must do ghusl before you pray regardless of the time. You should have timed waking up to the time of fajr.",
    "tags": ["Prayer", "Purity"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-have-a-problem-when-i-am-sleeping-sometimes-i-have-a-wet-dream-and-ghusl-becomes-fared-on-me-but-the-time-that-i-woke-up-was-right-before-sunrise-or-a-couple-of-minutes-before-what-shoul/",
    "date": "March 3, 2024 4:59 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If Allah knows everything what\u2019s going to happen and sees everything, created everything and controls everything, then why does He give us the free will to choose and then let us suffer or get rewards accordingly? If He knew everything beforehand who\u2019s going to do what, then what\u2019s the point of all these life and hereafter? What does Allah gain from it? And why did He create it in the first place?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If Allah admitted people to hell fire based on His knowledge, people would complain that if we were given the chance, we would not have sinned or disobeyed Allah. This is why Allah created them and gave them free will to choose and then holds them accountable for their choices.",
    "tags": ["Divine Will and Decree"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-allah-knows-everything-whats-going-to-happen-and-sees-everything-created-everything-and-controls-everything-then-why-does-he-give-us-the-free-will-to-choose-and-then-let-us-suffer-or/",
    "date": "February 28, 2024 10:40 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh, is it permissible to not get married for a young girl who fears child birth pain and operations",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This fear is baseless and satan is messing up with her head Millions and millions of women have been giving birth since Hawwa (eve) without any problem. Nevertheless, this is your choice and preference. So many women discovered this the hard way after it was too late that being alone without a husband or a child is way harder than childbirth",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-is-it-permissible-to-not-get-married-for-a-young-girl-who-fears-child-birth-pain-and-operations/",
    "date": "February 25, 2024 5:56 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I want to ask that a woman can cut her hairs at the end of umra to cum out from ihram.bcoz sum scholars says that u cant cut your own hairs bcoz you are in the state of ihram.now if cant then its really difficult to search sum one to cut the hairs.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem to cut her hair by herself.",
    "tags": ["Hajj and Umrah"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-want-to-ask-that-a-woman-can-cut-her-hairs-at-the-end-of-umra-to-cum-out-from-ihram-bcoz-sum-scholars-says-that-u-cant-cut-your-own-hairs-bcoz-you-are-in-the-state-of-ihram-now-if-cant-the/",
    "date": "February 20, 2024 7:41 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If i give someone book The sealed nectar. Is it going to be ongoing charity for me?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Yes, in sha Allah. As long as people would benefit from it, you will be rewarded.",
    "tags": ["Charity"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-i-give-someone-book-the-sealed-nectar-is-it-going-to-be-ongoing-charity-for-me/",
    "date": "February 17, 2024 3:08 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If i sneeze in salah while reciting al fatiha then is it permissible to say alhamdulillah mid recitation?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Yes.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-i-sneeze-in-salah-while-reciting-al-fatiha-then-is-it-permissible-to-say-alhamdulillah-mid-recitation/",
    "date": "February 14, 2024 11:50 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it allowed to differentiate among one\u2019s kid as Yaqoob (pbuh) did. He loved his two sons ( Yusuf pbuh and Bin Yameen) more than others, that\u2019s why other siblings became jealous.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: 1- Love is in the heart and one has no control over it. What is not permissible is to differentiate in treatment.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of the family", "Pedagogy education and upbringing"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-allowed-to-differentiate-among-ones-kid-as-yaqoob-pbuh-did-he-loved-his-two-sons-yusuf-pbuh-and-bin-yameen-more-than-others-thats-why-other-siblings-became-jea/",
    "date": "February 11, 2024 2:03 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If my wife is sick and I asked her to have intimacy but she refused due to her sickness and pain Is she sinful and cursed for rejecting the relation ship",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Of course not! Allah doesn\u2019t burden a soul beyond what it can bear.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-my-wife-is-sick-and-i-asked-her-to-have-intimacy-but-she-refused-due-to-her-sickness-and-pain-is-she-sinful-and-cursed-for-rejecting-the-relation-ship/",
    "date": "February 8, 2024 12:01 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh, is it Haram to sleep on your belly? Cause that\u2019s my favorite sleeping position",
    "answer": "ANSWER: The majority say that this is not permissible or at least it is makrooh and so do doctors. However, I don\u2019t believe that it is prohibited and Allah knows best.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-is-it-haram-to-sleep-on-your-belly-cause-thats-my-favorite-sleeping-position/",
    "date": "February 5, 2024 5:13 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I saw people label moslems as idol worshiper. What is the best respond for it?. Thank you in advance.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: When dogs bark, you ignore it and move on! No one in his right mind would fall on his hands and knees and bark back!",
    "tags": ["Religions"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-saw-people-label-moslems-as-idol-worshiper-what-is-the-best-respond-for-it-thank-you-in-advance/",
    "date": "February 3, 2024 5:42 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION:\u00a0Is there any Sunnah or barakah for using olive oil for hair and cooking etc\u2026?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: I don\u2019t recall any sunnah in this regard but of course it is a blessed oil as it was mentioned in the Quran",
    "tags": ["Other"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-there-any-sunnah-or-barakah-for-using-olive-oil-for-hair-and-cooking-etc/",
    "date": "January 31, 2024 5:31 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I wanted to know when washing the hands and wiping over the socks in wudu do i wash both hands or wipe both socks together at the same time or separately",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Both are permissible. The sunnah is to do it together.",
    "tags": ["Ablution (Wudhu)"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-wanted-to-know-when-washing-the-hands-and-wiping-over-the-socks-in-wudu-do-i-wash-both-hands-or-wipe-both-socks-together-at-the-same-time-or-separately/",
    "date": "January 28, 2024 9:51 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I do not work but I am given gift money year-round and I was wondering if Zakat is obliged on me even though these are not my individual earnings. This money is from graduation, Eid, and the likes. I use this money for personal needs/wants.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If this money reaches the nisab then yes, you must pay zakat on it, whether it\u2019s your hard earned money or gift.",
    "tags": ["Zakat"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-do-not-work-but-i-am-given-gift-money-year-round-and-i-was-wondering-if-zakat-is-obliged-on-me-even-though-these-are-not-my-individual-earnings-this-money-is-from-graduation-eid-and-the/",
    "date": "January 25, 2024 8:56 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I\u2019m living abroad with my wife and son. My parents wants to visit us for 10 days, but my wife doesn\u2019t like them coming as last time they came before 2 years and stayed for 3 months, there was misunderstanding between my wife and mother. As my mom keeps on nagging my wife even for small things. I\u2019m stuck in between and don\u2019t know what to do. Please advise",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Your wife should understand that these are your parents and that you love them and they can come and stay for a few days. It\u2019s not as if she has to live with them forever! You have a right to host them for 10 days without her complaining and she can stay out of their way and faces if she doesn\u2019t want to meet them.",
    "tags": ["Dealings and Attitudes with In-Laws", "Fiqh of Marriage"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-im-living-abroad-with-my-wife-and-son-my-parents-wants-to-visit-us-for-10-days-but-my-wife-doesnt-like-them-coming-as-last-time-they-came-before-2-years-and-stayed-for-3/",
    "date": "January 23, 2024 5:06 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it kufr to say \u201cI live for you, I\u2019d die for you\u201d to someone/read that sentence out loud from a poem?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not kufr as it is metaphorical",
    "tags": ["Other"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-kufr-to-say-i-live-for-you-id-die-for-you-to-someone-read-that-sentence-out-loud-from-a-poem/",
    "date": "January 20, 2024 9:35 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh do I say bathroom dua before or after stepping into bathroom",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Before.",
    "tags": ["Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-do-i-say-bathroom-dua-before-or-after-stepping-into-bathroom/",
    "date": "January 17, 2024 4:49 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh I killed a cockroach and there was alot of wetness from it. Is it najis?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It is an issue of dispute among scholars No one in his right mind, even if everyone says it is not najis, would still come close to that area, let alone pray on it!",
    "tags": ["Prayer", "Purity"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-i-killed-a-cockroach-and-there-was-alot-of-wetness-from-it-is-it-najis/",
    "date": "January 15, 2024 4:25 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If someone ask Allah or make dua near the grave of prophet thinking it is a place of seeking barakah, is it minor shirk? Or is it actually a place of seeking barakah",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If he is calling Allah alone thinking this place is a blessed place, this is an innovation and sinful.",
    "tags": ["Innovations", "Shirk and its different forms"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-someone-ask-allah-or-make-dua-near-the-grave-of-prophet-thinking-it-is-a-place-of-seeking-barakah-is-it-minor-shirk-or-is-it-actually-a-place-of-seeking-barakah/",
    "date": "January 12, 2024 6:07 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is earnimg through twitter monetization haram sheikh? is it permissible?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Where is the money coming from? If it is coming from ads that you allowed them to put on your account so that people would see, this is haram if the ads contain music, women or haram content.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Social Media"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-earnimg-through-twitter-monetization-haram-sheikh-is-it-permissible/",
    "date": "January 10, 2024 5:23 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Shaykh, one of my Mahrams (sufi) who celebrates the Mawlid sent me a message \u2013 \u201cRabi Al Awwal Mubaarak\u201d Is it ok if I reply \u062e\u064e\u064a\u0631\u0652 \u0645\u064f\u0628\u0627\u0631\u0643 as in our culture for replying to such greetings (wedding mubarak, etc) Or do I refrain in case she may send me a message on the Mawlid?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Refrain from responding.",
    "tags": ["Innovations"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-shaykh-one-of-my-mahrams-sufi-who-celebrates-the-mawlid-sent-me-a-message-rabi-al-awwal-mubaarak-is-it-ok-if-i-reply-%d8%ae%d9%8e%d9%8a%d8%b1%d9%92-%d9%85%d9%8f%d8%a8%d8%a7%d8%b1/",
    "date": "January 7, 2024 5:46 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it true that if someone has harmed and insulted someone else and that oppressed person makes dua and Allah avenged him in this life, will he not gain his good deeds in hereafter as the oppreaser got what he deserves in this life",
    "answer": "ANSWER: True! Allah doesn\u2019t punish an individual twice.",
    "tags": ["Punishments", "Rewards & Punishments", "Sins"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question/",
    "date": "January 5, 2024 4:57 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I forgot to wash my hands and rinse my nose when waking up and I immediately made wudu without doing this beforehand. Is my wudu and salah I prayed valid?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It\u2019s valid. Washing hands and rinsing nose is highly recommended after waking up, however its not mandatory.",
    "tags": ["Ablution (Wudhu)", "Other", "Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-forgot-to-wash-my-hands-and-rinse-my-nose-when-waking-up-and-i-immediately-made-wudu-without-doing-this-beforehand-is-my-wudu-and-salah-i-prayed-valid/",
    "date": "January 2, 2024 6:07 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh can I make money by watching ads though it can contain haram sounds\u2026",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Of course not, this is not permissible at all",
    "tags": ["Jobs"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-can-i-make-money-by-watching-ads-though-it-can-contain-haram-sounds/",
    "date": "December 31, 2023 4:31 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I\u2019m not able to decide. I\u2019m going to get married and the girl I\u2019m marrying said in a discussion that you might not find me vrgn due to her past relationship whr she did haraam many times.. What I should do? Please suggest\u2026",
    "answer": "ANSWER: She\u2019s not the last girl on earth! Move on and look for a pious muslimah who would be the mother of your children It\u2019s not permissible to ask about people\u2019s past life or their sins nor is it permissible to expose your own sins in front of ANYONE",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-im-not-able-to-decide-im-going-to-get-married-and-the-girl-im-marrying-said-in-a-discussion-that-you-might-not-find-me-vrgn-due-to-her-past-relationship-whr-she-did-haraam-many-times/",
    "date": "December 28, 2023 2:22 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is there any importance for gifting a Quran and Abaya to someone as in we will get reward if they read or wear it?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Of course, you will be rewarded everytime they read Quran from it.",
    "tags": ["Rewards & Punishments"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-there-any-importance-for-gifting-a-quran-and-abaya-to-someone-as-in-we-will-get-reward-if-they-read-or-wear-it/",
    "date": "December 25, 2023 5:10 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it possible for anyone to go for Hajj or umrah without Allah\u2019s invitation? I heard some scolers says that Hajj or umrah is the invitation of Allah. Only choosen people can get this chance but some people argue that people are not so good how can they are invited by Allah? I really don\u2019t know how to answer them.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: There is no such thing as invitation by Allah! If Allah wills it, people can go to perform hajj.",
    "tags": ["Hajj and Umrah"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-possible-for-anyone-to-go-for-hajj-or-umrah-without-allahs-invitation-i-heard-some-scolers-says-that-hajj-or-umrah-is-the-invitation-of-allah-only-choosen-people-can-get-thi/",
    "date": "December 23, 2023 5:23 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Can we offer solah in a room that has a picture of a human?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not recommended but the prayer is valid.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-can-we-offer-solah-in-a-room-that-has-a-picture-of-a-human/",
    "date": "December 20, 2023 4:04 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: In Salah, I recite Fatiha and Surah in Arabic by moving my lips but I also recite its meaning afterwards in my own language without moving my lips(in the heart). Thus, I find khushu in my prayers. Is this permissible to do?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If the meaning in English crosses your mind, this is fine. But if you pause for few minutes after reciting it in Arabic to do that in English in your head, this is an innovation and pausing in prayer without any valid reason and it would nullify it.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-in-salah-i-recite-fatiha-and-surah-in-arabic-by-moving-my-lips-but-i-also-recite-its-meaning-afterwards-in-my-own-language-without-moving-my-lipsin-the-heart-thus-i-find-khushu-in-my-pr/",
    "date": "December 18, 2023 4:09 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh, how to make Allah smile on us?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: When you follow Allah\u2019s commands to the letter and avoid all types of sins while coming with a pure heart, Allah is pleased with you.",
    "tags": ["Rewards & Punishments"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-how-to-make-allah-smile-on-us/",
    "date": "December 15, 2023 2:48 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Are men commanded or just recommended to treat their wives well?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: They are commanded to treat them well.",
    "tags": ["Character and Morals", "Kind Treatment of Spouses"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-are-men-commanded-or-just-recommended-to-treat-their-wives-well/",
    "date": "December 12, 2023 10:42 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I\u2019m a student i take tuition from a teacher who make questions for our final exam and he gives important question to his tuition students when he explains the topic and some of the students not getting such important question. So, is sinful if I take those questions for gatting good mark or percentage, Please explain",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It is not permissible to take private tuition with the same teacher who teaches you in the morning as this is a conflict of interest unless it is conducted in the same school and supervised by it.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-im-a-student-i-take-tuition-from-a-teacher-who-make-questions-for-our-final-exam-and-he-gives-important-question-to-his-tuition-students-when-he-explains-the-topic-and-some-of-the-students/",
    "date": "December 8, 2023 4:59 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it authentic to say certain dikr when going up and going down on the stairs",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No, this is not authentic. This thikr is said when going uphill and down hills while traveling",
    "tags": ["Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-authentic-to-say-certain-dikr-when-going-up-and-going-down-on-the-stairs/",
    "date": "December 4, 2023 2:42 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sir is it prohibited to look at the mirror during midnight. Please answer this .",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem providing that the lights are on!",
    "tags": ["Innovations"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sir-is-it-prohibited-to-look-at-the-mirror-during-midnight-please-answer-this/",
    "date": "December 1, 2023 2:40 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Should we enter the bathroom with left foot if it is a separate room from the toilet? I heard you say in the series going through Bulugh al Maram that we enter the toilet with our left foot because we are about to do an act that is not honourable. So what foot should I enter my bathroom to perform wudu or shower?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If there is a toilet in that room, you should enter with your left foot.",
    "tags": ["Etiquette, Morals and Heart-Softeners"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-should-we-enter-the-bathroom-with-left-foot-if-it-is-a-separate-room-from-the-toilet-i-heard-you-say-in-the-series-going-through-bulugh-al-maram-that-we-enter-the-toilet-with-our-left-foot/",
    "date": "November 28, 2023 12:55 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: The imam of my mosque always do congregational dua after each fard salah. I know its bidah. Each week he does tafsir on Friday night. After tafseer he does congregational dua and before it durood e Ibrahim in congregation. Without doing durood e Ibrahim with them can i join him in congregational dua only after the tafseer or will this be a bidah too?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem. However, I doubt that the knowledge you learn from him would be authentic if he is indulged in such innovations.",
    "tags": ["Innovations"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-the-imam-of-my-mosque-always-do-congregational-dua-after-each-fard-salah-i-know-its-bidah-each-week-he-does-tafsir-on-friday-night-after-tafseer-he-does-congregational-dua-and-before-it-d/",
    "date": "November 25, 2023 3:17 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: What is the ruling of saying \u201cWhat the f*ck\u201d? I need a pretty detailed answer.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is totally prohibited as Islam prohibits profanity.",
    "tags": ["Character and Morals", "Halal/Haram Matters"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-what-is-the-ruling-of-saying-what-the-fck-i-need-a-pretty-detailed-answer/",
    "date": "November 22, 2023 11:12 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I\u2019ve a photography account on instagram where I share random pictures (not pics of people). The acc isn\u2019t private and ofc i want my captures to reach as much poeple as possible and I\u2019ve many female followers too. Sometimes I share my mirror selfies on story with my face hidden.So is it haram for a man to share his picture where non mahram will see it?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in men sharing their pictures where nonmahrams may see him providing he is not fitha for women and that his awrah is properly covered.",
    "tags": ["Social Media"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-ive-a-photography-account-on-instagram-where-i-share-random-pictures-not-pics-of-people-the-acc-isnt-private-and-ofc-i-want-my-captures-to-reach-as-much-poeple-as-possible-and-ive-m/",
    "date": "November 18, 2023 5:32 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Palastine: Shiekh, I cnt bear this pain as this is going beyond my tolerance..i pray tahajjud still I dnt feel peace in my heart..please what shall I do?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: There were calamities at the time of the prophet salla Allahu alaihi wa sallam where many of his companions were brutally murdered and mutilated, among them was his own beloved uncle Hamzah. This did not stop him from sleeping, eating and enjoying life! Yes he grieved over them but moved on and did not live a life of mourning and sadness.",
    "tags": ["Psychological and Social Problems"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-palastine-shiekh-i-cnt-bear-this-pain-as-this-is-going-beyond-my-tolerance-i-pray-tahajjud-still-i-dnt-feel-peace-in-my-heart-please-what-shall-i-do/",
    "date": "November 16, 2023 7:20 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Can i pray on a prayer mat which has my name on it?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-can-i-pray-on-a-prayer-mat-which-has-my-name-on-it/",
    "date": "November 10, 2023 6:51 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My relatives living in USA told me that when they need any tools or devices(laptop, phone, watch) for a few days they buy them from a shop and after they are done using it those they return the tools to the shop getting a full refund. They also said that many people use clothes like this too. They all just use the stuff without really paying. Is that okay to do?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Of course not! This is cheating and Prophet salla Allahu alaihi wa sallam said a person who cheats is not from among us and lying is a major sin! Only cheap people would do such heinous acts!",
    "tags": ["Character and Morals"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-relatives-living-in-usa-told-me-that-when-they-need-any-tools-or-deviceslaptop-phone-watch-for-a-few-days-they-buy-them-from-a-shop-and-after-they-are-done-using-it-those-they-return/",
    "date": "November 8, 2023 1:40 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: During prayer, do i need reciet the surah in sequence or i can reciet randomly which ever surah i want. I watch your youtube video on this question but i don\u2019t undertand enough from it, can you please just clearify me about it?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You can recite any surah you want randomly, no need to recite in sequence.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-during-prayer-do-i-need-reciet-the-surah-in-sequence-or-i-can-reciet-randomly-which-ever-surah-i-want-i-watch-your-youtube-video-on-this-question-but-i-dont-undertand-enough-from-it-can/",
    "date": "November 5, 2023 9:32 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Does talking during ablution break ablution?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No, it does not.",
    "tags": ["Ablution (Wudhu)"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-does-talking-during-ablution-break-ablution/",
    "date": "November 3, 2023 2:10 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I never knew shaving the beard is Haram I thought leaving the beard is sunnah",
    "answer": "ANSWER: All scholars of different schools of thought agree that shaving it is haram and sinful.",
    "tags": [
      "Beautification & Cosmetic Suregry",
      "Halal/Haram Matters",
      "Men Clothing"
    ],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-never-knew-shaving-the-beard-is-haram-i-thought-leaving-the-beard-is-sunnah/",
    "date": "October 31, 2023 6:40 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My cousins and relatives continuously glare at me and say that I look beautiful and all but never says Masha Allah How can I not sound rude and ask them to stop continuously repeating one thing as I fear evil eye",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You must observe your morning and evening athkaar to be protected from evil eye and as long as you do, no harm will come to you by the Grace of Allah. You can advise them with good manners, wisdom, knowledge, and diplomacy to say \u201cAllah humma barik\u201d.",
    "tags": ["Jinn, Witchcraft, Black Magic and the Evil Eye"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-cousins-and-relatives-continuously-glare-at-me-and-say-that-i-look-beautiful-and-all-but-never-says-masha-allah-how-can-i-not-sound-rude-and-ask-them-to-stop-continuously-repeating-one-th/",
    "date": "October 27, 2023 7:31 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: When i\u2019m confused in making decisions should i pray istikharah? (Like sometimes i\u2019m sure to do that, sometimes i\u2019m not sure)",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You should pray istikhara when you have already made up your mind over what you are going to do and NOT when you are confused and not determined!",
    "tags": ["Istikhara"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-when-im-confused-in-making-decisions-should-i-pray-istikharah-like-sometimes-im-sure-to-do-that-sometimes-im-not-sure/",
    "date": "October 23, 2023 1:17 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it okay to raise hand while Saying Assalamu alaikum to People you meet or while passing by?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not from the sunnah. However, if such people are at a distance and won\u2019t hear your salam, raising the hand in such a case is fine.",
    "tags": ["Etiquette, Morals and Heart-Softeners"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-okay-to-raise-hand-while-saying-assalamu-alaikum-to-people-you-meet-or-while-passing-by/",
    "date": "October 19, 2023 4:59 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it haram to upload food pictures in social media like in Instagram stories and all",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not haram but its not recommended due to the possibility of catching evil eye.",
    "tags": ["Social Media"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-haram-to-upload-food-pictures-in-social-media-like-in-instagram-stories-and-all/",
    "date": "October 12, 2023 3:56 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If something is bought through riba, does that count as something you bought with haram money and have to give sadaqah in the worth of the product? Because my earnings are halal in shaa Allah but the way of purchase was not.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If a person buys something permissible with a riba-based loan,\u00a0he has to repent to Allaah, and there is nothing wrong with him keeping or making use of the permissible thing, and he does not have to sell it.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Riba"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-something-is-bought-through-riba-does-that-count-as-something-you-bought-with-haram-money-and-have-to-give-sadaqah-in-the-worth-of-the-product-because-my-earnings-are-halal-in-shaa-alla/",
    "date": "October 8, 2023 2:51 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is there a specific dua to recite after ghusl done for major impurity?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No.",
    "tags": ["Purity", "Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-there-a-specific-dua-to-recite-after-ghusl-done-for-major-impurity/",
    "date": "October 5, 2023 1:33 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: What\u2019s the ruling on calling people as \u2018lord\u2019? Is it shirk?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in this.",
    "tags": ["Shirk and its different forms"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-whats-the-ruling-on-calling-people-as-lord-is-it-shirk/",
    "date": "October 1, 2023 2:48 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My question is can men wear mix colour shirts or tshirts which have orange colour in them. As orange colour is usually worn by buddhist monks, hindu priests, non believers etc. And if we wear such colours does it effect the validity of our prayers?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in this as long as it\u2019s normal in your community and you wouldn\u2019t stand out in the crowd.",
    "tags": ["Beautification & Cosmetic Suregry", "Men Clothing"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-question-is-can-men-wear-mix-colour-shirts-or-tshirts-which-have-orange-colour-in-them-as-orange-colour-is-usually-worn-by-buddhist-monks-hindu-priests-non-believers-etc-and-if-we-wea/",
    "date": "September 28, 2023 8:54 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I have a friend, Allah has blessed him with more rizq than me, every time we get into a disagreement he belittles me and always refers to the fact how he is more successful than me and I am a \u2018loser\u2019. I know that he has been doing tax fraud for years. If I report him out of anger would I be sinful?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You are sinful because you are doing this out of spite and envy! You must cut off all communications with such an arrogant person and your friendship to him is toxic to you and dangerous to him as you are envious and can\u2019t be trusted.",
    "tags": ["Character and Morals"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-have-a-friend-allah-has-blessed-him-with-more-rizq-than-me-every-time-we-get-into-a-disagreement-he-belittles-me-and-always-refers-to-the-fact-how-he-is-more-successful-than-me-and-i-am/",
    "date": "September 25, 2023 1:32 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it permissible to Eat the meat slaughtered by a shia?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If they follow the deviant Shia aqeedah and curse the companions and mothers of the believers then it\u2019s not permissible to eat meat slaughtered by them as they are not Muslims.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Sects"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-permissible-to-eat-the-meat-slaughtered-by-a-shia/",
    "date": "September 22, 2023 1:49 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I pray fajr at home and quickly because if i wash my face and go to masjid then i cant sleep after that. If i dont sleep i cant concentrate at the other prayers and i feel miserable and cant do other daily activities. Is it permissable for me to pray fajr quickly with not much khushoo and at home as a man",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If the masjid is within your vicinity, it is not permissible to pray home like women and children and ill people.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-pray-fajr-at-home-and-quickly-because-if-i-wash-my-face-and-go-to-masjid-then-i-cant-sleep-after-that-if-i-dont-sleep-i-cant-concentrate-at-the-other-prayers-and-i-feel-miserable-and-cant/",
    "date": "September 19, 2023 3:44 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: In morning and evening azkaar, there are some azkaar which have Dua in them, are we supposed to raise our hands for those azkaar? What is Sunnah about it?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No, you should not raise your hands as this is dhikr.",
    "tags": ["Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-in-morning-and-evening-azkaar-there-are-some-azkaar-which-have-dua-in-them-are-we-supposed-to-raise-our-hands-for-those-azkaar-what-is-sunnah-about-it/",
    "date": "September 16, 2023 11:51 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh, I\u2019ve become a practicing muslim & intend to provide islamic education to my 2 children. But after high school or similar institutions, there is no islamic university in our country. They\u2019ll have to study in a mixed environment then for higher studies. I believe it would be disastrous for their imaan & akhlaq. What should I do to protect them as a father? Pls advise.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Once you instill solid Islamic values in your children from an early age, in sha Allah they will apply that in their future lives as well. You must make lots of dua to keep them steadfast.",
    "tags": ["Pedagogy education and upbringing"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-ive-become-a-practicing-muslim-intend-to-provide-islamic-education-to-my-2-children-but-after-high-school-or-similar-institutions-there-is-no-islamic-university-in-our-c/",
    "date": "September 13, 2023 1:14 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My parents are going to umrah In Sha Allah.My father wants to take their funeral cloth to Saudi and wash them with jamjam water as it is a sacred water and bring it back in our country.Wil it be an innovation?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Yes. This is an innovation.",
    "tags": ["Funerals", "Hajj and Umrah", "Innovations"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-parents-are-going-to-umrah-in-sha-allah-my-father-wants-to-take-their-funeral-cloth-to-saudi-and-wash-them-with-jamjam-water-as-it-is-a-sacred-water-and-bring-it-back-in-our-country-wil-i/",
    "date": "September 10, 2023 12:16 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If I am done with my adhkar and someone is praying behind me what should I do if I want to go home and there is no sutra in the masjid.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You can get up and go without passing in between his standing position and his sujood spot.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-i-am-done-with-my-adhkar-and-someone-is-praying-behind-me-what-should-i-do-if-i-want-to-go-home-and-there-is-no-sutra-in-the-masjid/",
    "date": "September 6, 2023 2:49 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: People buy Kafan (deadboy cloth) for themselves in advance during their lifetime and keep them. Is it allowed? Then people take it to Makkah and get it washed (ghusl) in zamzam water. They also get different ayats and duas written or imprinted on them. I have never heard of this before and it turns out that this is a practice on a huge level amongst Muslims in the Subcontinent (India/Pak).",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in buying the kafan but taking it to makkah and washing it with zamzam and writing ayahs on it is totally prohibited and an innovation.",
    "tags": ["Funerals", "Innovations"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-people-buy-kafan-deadboy-cloth-for-themselves-in-advance-during-their-lifetime-and-keep-them-is-it-allowed-then-people-take-it-to-makkah-and-get-it-washed-ghusl-in-zamzam-water-they-a/",
    "date": "September 3, 2023 5:30 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I\u2019m a woman.After interc*urse I take major ghusl. And after few minutes something transparent comes out. Is this impact on my ghusl?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This does not impact the ghusl but it impacts your wudhu.",
    "tags": ["Purity"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-im-a-woman-after-intercurse-i-take-major-ghusl-and-after-few-minutes-something-transparent-comes-out-is-this-impact-on-my-ghusl/",
    "date": "August 31, 2023 11:57 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh, what is the ruling on blowing on Others after making duaa or blowing on yourself after dua then rubbing the body?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not from the sunnah and it is an innovation. One can blow on his hands and wipe his body if he is reciting ruqya for healing and cure.",
    "tags": ["Innovations", "Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-what-is-the-ruling-on-blowing-on-others-after-making-duaa-or-blowing-on-yourself-after-dua-then-rubbing-the-body/",
    "date": "August 28, 2023 9:01 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it sunnah to pronounce isti\u2019aza before reading the translation of the meanings of the Quran?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No. There\u2019s no problem if you do though.",
    "tags": ["Reading/Reciting the Quran"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-sunnah-to-pronounce-istiaza-before-reading-the-translation-of-the-meanings-of-the-quran/",
    "date": "August 25, 2023 7:55 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Ya sheikh why are you extremely strict you should be kind sometimes",
    "answer": "ANSWER: I am kind when kindness is needed and harsh when people are of need to be disciplined and waken up! I don\u2019t look for popularity or praising of people. It is very easy for you to criticize people when you yourself had never encountered working with the public with their many different shades and kinds. Therefore, you won\u2019t be able to understand until you work in customer service and deal with different types and levels of people. Then you would appreciate what the likes of me are doing and you would then wonder how I was able to tolerate such people!",
    "tags": ["Knowledge & Propagation"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-ya-sheikh-why-are-you-extremely-strict-you-should-be-kind-sometimes/",
    "date": "August 22, 2023 10:48 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I\u2019m a finance lawyer in a law firm. Our clients are banks and borrowers. We prepare loan documents (interest bearing) and security/collateral docs. We are paid a fee from the borrower for this work. Is this job permissible, makruh or haram? I\u2019m not employed by any bank and don\u2019t consume the interest myself.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If you assist people in paying off their interest based loans or reaching a settlement or rescheduling such loans or to enforce them pay off the interest and the likes, all such work is assisting on riba.",
    "tags": ["Jobs", "Riba"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-im-a-finance-lawyer-in-a-law-firm-our-clients-are-banks-and-borrowers-we-prepare-loan-documents-interest-bearing-and-security-collateral-docs-we-are-paid-a-fee-from-the-borrowe/",
    "date": "August 20, 2023 2:42 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Regarding Jummah Prayer in my area where I work there is no mosque nearby / or I don\u2019t know about it that there is one. Am I obligated to attend Jummah?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Yes, as long as there is even a single masjid that conducts Friday prayer in your city, you must attend it even if its far off since its only once a week.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-regarding-jummah-prayer-in-my-area-where-i-work-there-is-no-mosque-nearby-or-i-dont-know-about-it-that-there-is-one-am-i-obligated-to-attend-jummah/",
    "date": "August 18, 2023 12:26 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh, I was in a Haram relationship for 4 years and now I\u2019m out of it after my proposal for nikkah was rejected by her, I was not a practicing Muslim now I\u2019m practicing Islam , my main concern is I\u2019m left with gifts from her such as clothes etc what do I do of them as I don\u2019t want to reach out to her for returning them.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in using them. However, if this reminds you of her and chances are that you would get back with her due to this it\u2019s best to not keep them. Give them away in charity.",
    "tags": ["Pre-Marital Relations"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-i-was-in-a-haram-relationship-for-4-years-and-now-im-out-of-it-after-my-proposal-for-nikkah-was-rejected-by-her-i-was-not-a-practicing-muslim-now-im-practicing-islam-my-main-c/",
    "date": "August 15, 2023 4:02 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Should i tell my future wife that my parents often mad to each other (uncondusif family situation), bcs i didnt want her to be upset if she knows after mariage or it is considered as telling family aib which is prohibited?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is of no concern to her or her family as she is marrying you and not them. Respect your parents and do not go around telling people about their flaws.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage", "Fiqh of the family"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-should-i-tell-my-future-wife-that-my-parents-often-mad-to-each-other-uncondusif-family-situation-bcs-i-didnt-want-her-to-be-upset-if-she-knows-after-mariage-or-it-is-considered-as-telling/",
    "date": "August 12, 2023 5:10 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Shaikh i want to ask you that is there any dua for gusul? how to do niyyah for gusul and can we do niyyah inside the washroom?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: There is no dua for doing ghusl. The intention is in the heart.",
    "tags": ["Innovations", "Purity", "Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-shaikh-i-want-to-ask-you-that-is-there-any-dua-for-gusul-how-to-do-niyyah-for-gusul-and-can-we-do-niyyah-inside-the-washroom/",
    "date": "August 9, 2023 10:03 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh can we turn our back to Quran while its open and we are reading and when we are not reading it?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in this whatsoever!",
    "tags": ["Quran", "Reading/Reciting the Quran"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-can-we-turn-our-back-to-quran-while-its-open-and-we-are-reading-and-when-we-are-not-reading-it/",
    "date": "August 7, 2023 11:09 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I used to go in ruku without finishing surah Al-Faatihah in the silent salah but know I know so do I have to make up the prayers.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You can\u2019t repeat them as the time is over and gone. Repent to Allah and do good deeds while feeling remorseful for your ignorance.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-used-to-go-in-ruku-without-finishing-surah-al-faatihah-in-the-silent-salah-but-know-i-know-so-do-i-have-to-make-up-the-prayers/",
    "date": "August 5, 2023 2:46 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My family doesnt wake up for fajr, I try waking them up sometimes, but they dont. Am i sinful if i dont try wake them up daily (since i find it tiresome and time consuming)",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If they specifically tell you not to wake them up then you\u2019re not sinful. Leave them alone as they are adults and accountable for their actions.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-family-doesnt-wake-up-for-fajr-i-try-waking-them-up-sometimes-but-they-dont-am-i-sinful-if-i-dont-try-wake-them-up-daily-since-i-find-it-tiresome-and-time-consuming/",
    "date": "August 2, 2023 4:09 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If i get my period during prayer but i don\u2019t know so i still continue the prayer does it mean i won\u2019t get ajr for the prayer and my duas made during the prayer aren\u2019t valid?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If you did not know about it until you had finished your prayer, you will be rewarded in Sha Allah.",
    "tags": ["Menstruation and post-natal bleeding", "Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-i-get-my-period-during-prayer-but-i-dont-know-so-i-still-continue-the-prayer-does-it-mean-i-wont-get-ajr-for-the-prayer-and-my-duas-made-during-the-prayer-arent-valid/",
    "date": "July 31, 2023 3:41 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it permissible to expose own sins or others to know about the ruling of it such as: Checking if it\u2019s haram If\u2026 , What is the solution\u2026 , If he does this sin\u2026 What should he do?, \u2026)",
    "answer": "ANSWER: The question is not clear. It\u2019s too generic. Ask a specific question with examples. It\u2019s not permissible to expose your sins nor to talk about other\u2019s sins except in one situation and this is when you are genuinely seeking advice from someone in how to move on or solve such problems.",
    "tags": ["Sins"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-permissible-to-expose-own-sins-or-others-to-know-about-the-ruling-of-it-such-as-checking-if-its-haram-if-what-is-the-solution-if-he-does-this-sin/",
    "date": "July 28, 2023 4:49 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: As some scientists claim climate change is due to human behaviour while others deny this claim saying we shouldn\u2019t mind C02, what should be the stance of muslim regarding climate change ? (For example, should we reduce car use to reduce CO2 or not? )",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is a scientific issue and as long as science supports it and nothing in Islam opposes it, we should believe it.",
    "tags": ["Other"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-as-some-scientists-claim-climate-change-is-due-to-human-behaviour-while-others-deny-this-claim-saying-we-shouldnt-mind-c02-what-should-be-the-stance-of-muslim-regarding-climate-change/",
    "date": "July 26, 2023 5:46 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: As a girl, my mom wants me to attend Arabi classes for the Alim course, but I don\u2019t want to go bcoz the teacher\u2019s practices concern me. They suggest us making up missed prayers with \u2018khaza\u2019 & other innovations such as reciting yasin after fajr, fatah after zohr & so on. The teacher puts pressure on my mom to send me! Am i sinful for not going there & even disobeying my mom? Need your advice Sheikh",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You must not attend such classes where innovation is taught.",
    "tags": [
      "Fiqh of the family",
      "Halal/Haram Matters",
      "Innovations",
      "Knowledge & Propagation"
    ],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-as-a-girl-my-mom-wants-me-to-attend-arabi-classes-for-the-alim-course-but-i-dont-want-to-go-bcoz-the-teachers-practices-concern-me-they-suggest-us-making-up-missed-prayers-with-khaz/",
    "date": "July 23, 2023 3:09 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Maghrib and isha\u2019a were joined in our local masjid without any of the conditions being met, the sky being quite cloudy was the basis of thier decision. I was in a dilema wether to correct them while the iqama was being said, leave the rows, or join them. But i feared that if i didn\u2019t join there wouldn\u2019t be a congregation to pray isha with at the normal time. Was my prayer invalid since i knew?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Yes. You must repeat your isha.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-maghrib-and-ishaa-were-joined-in-our-local-masjid-without-any-of-the-conditions-being-met-the-sky-being-quite-cloudy-was-the-basis-of-thier-decision-i-was-in-a-dilema-wether-to-correct-t/",
    "date": "July 21, 2023 2:17 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Does shaitan only misguide and whisper to the muslims or does he also do it to the kafirs?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: He does it to the kafirs as well.",
    "tags": ["Jinn, Witchcraft, Black Magic and the Evil Eye"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-does-shaitan-only-misguide-and-whisper-to-the-muslims-or-does-he-also-do-it-to-the-kafirs/",
    "date": "July 17, 2023 10:12 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Can I sell old money for higher value for e.g can I sell a rare \u00a31 coin for \u00a310 if these coins are old so they are no longer used for transactions rather they are bought to be kept in a collection. However these coins could also be traded for coins that can be used for transactions.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If these are not in circulation anymore, and they are not gold or silver, these are not currency anymore.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-can-i-sell-old-money-for-higher-value-for-e-g-can-i-sell-a-rare-1-coin-for-10-if-these-coins-are-old-so-they-are-no-longer-used-for-transactions-rather-they-are-bought-to-be-kept-in-a-collec/",
    "date": "July 16, 2023 3:00 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If I work as a baker can I also make cakes for babyshowers and birthdays?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Baking cakes for birthdays and baby showers and other Haram events is not permissible.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Jobs"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-i-work-as-a-baker-can-i-also-make-cakes-for-babyshowers-and-birthdays/",
    "date": "July 13, 2023 1:56 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it mandatory for a girl to serve her mother and father all her life, and don\u2019t get married, while others refuse to serve them!? What\u2019s ruling in Islam?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If there is no one to take care of them and if they\u2019re not self sufficient and the would be husband wouldn\u2019t agree her to take care of them after marriage then yes, she must give priority to looking after them.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage", "Fiqh of the family"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-mandatory-for-a-girl-to-serve-her-mother-and-father-all-her-life-and-dont-get-married-while-others-refuse-to-serve-them-whats-ruling-in-islam/",
    "date": "July 10, 2023 6:17 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Someone is changing clothes near open cupboard where there is quran and books that have Allah name. is this sinful?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not sinful.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Quran"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-someone-is-changing-clothes-near-open-cupboard-where-there-is-quran-and-books-that-have-allah-name-is-this-sinful/",
    "date": "July 7, 2023 4:01 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I know of a person who is very lazy to remove her public hair. She removes it max thrice in 1 year if not lesser. She knows its an obligation to remove every 40 days but is still lazy. What does Islam say about such a person.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: She is sinful since its mandatory to remove the pubic and underarm hairs within 40 days.",
    "tags": ["Purity"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-know-of-a-person-who-is-very-lazy-to-remove-her-public-hair-she-removes-it-max-thrice-in-1-year-if-not-lesser-she-knows-its-an-obligation-to-remove-every-40-days-but-is-still-lazy-what/",
    "date": "July 4, 2023 9:53 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I was wondering if we could rely upon scholar ibn Taymiyyah\u2019s statement that it\u2019s the fathers\u2019s choice to name his children if he and his wife are in dispute as he didn\u2019t mention the evidence to this from either Qur\u2019an or Hadith? And in general can we rely upon scholar\u2019s statements even if they don\u2019t mention the evidence to their claims?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: The statement is 100% true. It is the sole right of the father to name his children as they would be carrying his name.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage", "Pedagogy education and upbringing"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-was-wondering-if-we-could-rely-upon-scholar-ibn-taymiyyahs-statement-that-its-the-fatherss-choice-to-name-his-children-if-he-and-his-wife-are-in-dispute-as-he-di/",
    "date": "June 26, 2023 5:40 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Me and my family were recently at the Prophet\u2019s Mosque, and I noticed that almost all of the people who pray there, pray 2 rakats sunnah after adhan of every prayer (they already performed tahiyyatul masjid as I\u2019ve seen), is this permissible? This is the same case here in Masjid Al haram in Makkah.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is from the sunnah to perform 2 rakah prayer between adhan and iqamah except for fajr.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-me-and-my-family-were-recently-at-the-prophets-mosque-and-i-noticed-that-almost-all-of-the-people-who-pray-there-pray-2-rakats-sunnah-after-adhan-of-every-prayer-they-already-performed/",
    "date": "June 24, 2023 2:37 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh what are the Benifits of reciting subhanallah wa alhumdullilah wa lailaha illalah wa Allahuakbar. What rewards or benefits do we get",
    "answer": "ANSWER: There are many benefits for that as various hadeeths cover it. The prophet salla Allahu alaihi wa sallam said that the most beloved words to Allah after the Quran are these four phrases.",
    "tags": ["Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-what-are-the-benifits-of-reciting-subhanallah-wa-alhumdullilah-wa-lailaha-illalah-wa-allahuakbar-what-rewards-or-benefits-do-we-get/",
    "date": "June 23, 2023 2:03 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is sleeping after asr prayer considered haram/makrooh?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It\u2019s neither haram nor makrooh as long as you get up and pray maghrib on time.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-sleeping-after-asr-prayer-considered-haram-makrooh/",
    "date": "June 21, 2023 1:29 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Men nowadays expect their wife to contribute financially. Nd who are eager to pay for their wives, in many cases- they humiliate their wife saying \u2013 I feed u, u r lazy, u can\u2019t earn a penny, you sat idly at home doing nothing. Now what should I do as a young girl. How can I do a job when many job makes me compromise the Hijab and requires interaction with non-mahram men?i also cant accpet such wor",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You need to choose your husband carefully and make it clear to him that you are not willing to work as real men are the sole breadwinners in a Muslim house.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-men-nowadays-expect-their-wife-to-contribute-financially-nd-who-are-eager-to-pay-for-their-wives-in-many-cases-they-humiliate-their-wife-saying-i-feed-u-u-r-lazy-u-cant-earn-a-penny/",
    "date": "June 19, 2023 2:03 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh we often see Non-Muslims saying bad things about Prophet S.A.W and Islam on social media.Should we answer them or ignore them.Sometimes they say things one can\u2019t even imagine.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: When dogs bark, do you fall down on your hands and knees to bark back?",
    "tags": [
      "Biography of the Prophet salla Allahu alahi wa sallam",
      "Religions"
    ],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-we-often-see-non-muslims-saying-bad-things-about-prophet-s-a-w-and-islam-on-social-media-should-we-answer-them-or-ignore-them-sometimes-they-say-things-one-cant-even-imagine/",
    "date": "June 16, 2023 1:04 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh, is i am sinful if i go out with my wife and children without asking my mother\u2019s permission? as she always create a fuss when we leave the house without taking her with us, she curse me for leaving her alone in house\u2026I don\u2019t know if this is right or wrong as my wife also don\u2019t want her to go with us. Is my wife has right to object?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Your mother has no right in interfering in your married life at all. You can DEFINITELY take your wife and kids anywhere you want without taking your mother along or even informing her! You can compensate your mother by taking her alone with you or with your kids without your wife to wherever it pleases her.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of the family", "Kind Treatment of Spouses"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-is-i-am-sinful-if-i-go-out-with-my-wife-and-children-without-asking-my-mothers-permission-as-she-always-create-a-fuss-when-we-leave-the-house-without-taking-her-with-us-she-curse/",
    "date": "June 12, 2023 8:33 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: In sujood al sahw do you say the takbir of movement before going into sujood and when coming back up? And say rabbighfirli twice when sitting?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You say the takbeer while going to sujood and while coming back up and you must say Rabbighfirli in between the two prostrations.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-in-sujood-al-sahw-do-you-say-the-takbir-of-movement-before-going-into-sujood-and-when-coming-back-up-and-say-rabbighfirli-twice-when-sitting/",
    "date": "June 12, 2023 1:31 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I was a shia (twelver/imamiyya) before & after sometime I left shi\u2019ism and stopped praying and fasting for about 6/7 years due to misguidance thinking islam is not for me. Alhamdulillah, recently I reverted back to straight path of Islam this time. I was wondering the rules for me regarding those missed prayers/fasts?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Nothing to be done about them as you were not Muslim at that time. Thank Allah and praise Him for guiding you and do righteous deeds and Allah will forgive your previous sins.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-was-a-shia-twelver-imamiyya-before-after-sometime-i-left-shiism-and-stopped-praying-and-fasting-for-about-6-7-years-due-to-misguidance-thinking-islam-is-not-for-me-alhamdulillah-re/",
    "date": "June 9, 2023 5:49 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh my father does udhiyah every year \u0627\u064e\u0644\u0652\u062d\u064e\u0645\u0652\u062f\u064f \u0644\u0650\u0644\u064e\u0651\u0670\u0647\u0650 and that is one lamb for the family of 4 who lives under him; including himself ( my brother lives abroad with his wife and two kids and he sometimes either share the money or do it completely. I have been earning for 1.5 year and i saved money from comity to do it this year. Sheikh i wanted to know if i can pay for it under my mother\u2019s name",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This udhiya is sufficient for your father and all those living under his roof regardless whether they are earning or not. Your brother who lives abroad has to offer his own on behalf of himself and his family.",
    "tags": ["Slaughtering"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-my-father-does-udhiyah-every-year-%d8%a7%d9%8e%d9%84%d9%92%d8%ad%d9%8e%d9%85%d9%92%d8%af%d9%8f-%d9%84%d9%90%d9%84%d9%8e%d9%91%d9%b0%d9%87%d9%90-and-that-is-one-lamb-for-the-family-of/",
    "date": "June 6, 2023 12:21 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Halal Dating in Islam I like a guy and he is in my university with me. We are not in a physical relationship but plan on marrying once we\u2019re done with our degree which is in 2 years. I haven\u2019t told my parents yet since they will say that this is not the right time and will ask me to cut contact with him while his parents know that he likes someone and is planning on marrying them. What should I do in this situation?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Either you are pleasing Allah or pleasing satan! No doubt that by being in contact with this individual, you are displeasing Allah and tarnishing your parents\u2019 reputation as women from honored families do not engage in such premarital relationships. You will soon fall weak and fall into physical relationships and fornication which is the route for your destruction in this life and in the hereafter unless you make an end to it. You must break off all communication with him and repent to Allah while showing deep remorse and sincerity for having any communication with him in the first place.",
    "tags": ["Pre-Marital Relations"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-halal-dating-in-islam-i-like-a-guy-and-he-is-in-my-university-with-me-we-are-not-in-a-physical-relationship-but-plan-on-marrying-once-were-done-with-our-degree-which-is-in-2-years/",
    "date": "June 3, 2023 5:43 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh I saw recently one of the questions about supershop discount.in my area the supershop didnt take any money from me,just as I am very regular customer so they offered me membership card &I accepted it.but next process is same that after certain amount they\u2019ll give me points which\u2019ll be considered like somw taka.is it also prohibited for me to use the card?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If they gave you this membership for free, this is fine. But if you have to pay anything for it, this is prohibited.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-i-saw-recently-one-of-the-questions-about-supershop-discount-in-my-area-the-supershop-didnt-take-any-money-from-mejust-as-i-am-very-regular-customer-so-they-offered-me-membership-car/",
    "date": "June 1, 2023 2:29 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh i have a question,I am nikahified only and rukhsati has not been done yet but after nikaah my mother didn\u2019t let me to talk to my husband on calls according to her there is no need to stay connected on calls before rukhasti.She thought talking to your husband is sin and always scolds me for talking to my husband and this irritates me everytime.What should i do?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: What she\u2019s saying is totally wrong. He\u2019s your husband and you can definitely talk with him and even go out for dinners, shopping etc with him. Talk to him behind her back!",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-i-have-a-questioni-am-nikahified-only-and-rukhsati-has-not-been-done-yet-but-after-nikaah-my-mother-didnt-let-me-to-talk-to-my-husband-on-calls-according-to-her-there-is-no/",
    "date": "May 30, 2023 9:00 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I am in my iddah period and my husband and i have been intimate but he has no intention of recounciling. Does being intimate during this time recouncile the marriage? Is there any evidences such as hadiths concerning the intimacy/foreplay during iddah period Please help me if you can. I am in my iddah and my husband still wants to be intimate with me kissing hugg",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It is not permissible for him to be intimate with you during the time of iddah without the intention of reconciliation. Would this impact the iddah or not, this is an issue of dispute. Sheikh ibn Othaimeen says that the iddah is still valid but he is sinful I am inclined to say that this iddah is broken and by having intercourse, this is considered revoking of the divorce and they are back as man and wife, and Allah knows best.",
    "tags": ["Divorce", "Waiting Period of widow or divorcee"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-am-in-my-iddah-period-and-my-husband-and-i-have-been-intimate-but-he-has-no-intention-of-recounciling-does-being-intimate-during-this-time-recouncile-the-marriage-is-there-any-evidences/",
    "date": "May 28, 2023 4:23 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I suffer from waswas and don\u2019t want to commit kufr. Many perverts in India has special lust for MUSLIM WOMEN (just because they are Muslimah) If one let\u2019s his womenfolk go out without hijab, isn\u2019t he creating a chance for such enemies of Islam to lust after them? Their action is kufr, right? so will he be helping/not preventing kufr action?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This type of logic is quite weird and stupid! Such a dayyouth doesn\u2019t have to worry about the enemies of Islam running after his womenfolk or Muslim perverts designing them! It\u2019s all the same! They are all looking for public toilets and this dayyouth is providing that to them. This is a major sin but it is not kufr! Thinking about such issues means that you suffer from a mental disorder that is hampering your thought process and engaging you in trivial issues that are distracting you from learning Islam, enjoying prayer and finding the sweetness of Iman! Try to move out of such whispers of satan and learn your religion properly instead of engaging in such fruitless thoughts!",
    "tags": ["Women clothing"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-suffer-from-waswas-and-dont-want-to-commit-kufr-many-perverts-in-india-has-special-lust-for-muslim-women-just-because-they-are-muslimah-if-one-lets-his-womenfolk-go-out-without-hi/",
    "date": "May 25, 2023 3:31 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh did I leave Islam if I said what justice is this to Allah or you like to bother me as I face life? I repeated shahada had and have left Islam anxiety.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Yes, you have left the fold of Islam if you had said this to Allah complaining of His decree.",
    "tags": ["Apostasy"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-did-i-leave-islam-if-i-said-what-justice-is-this-to-allah-or-you-like-to-bother-me-as-i-face-life-i-repeated-shahada-had-and-have-left-islam-anxiety/",
    "date": "May 23, 2023 6:32 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: A lot of people openly criticize Muslim leaders because they have trade relations or political alliance with countries that oppress Muslims. Is it wrong of me to say that perhaps this can be seen as a strategic approach to help those Muslims as I know it\u2019s also wrong to openly criticize Muslim leaders and we should give the benefit of the doubt A lot of people openly criticize Muslim leaders",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It is best that you don\u2019t engage with such people in arguments as they have nothing better to do than to argue and debate all the time. Focus on learning your religion and gaining knowledge that would draw you closer to Allah rather than defending rulers or justifying their actions! Such arguments corrupt the hearts.",
    "tags": ["Islamic Politics"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-a-lot-of-people-openly-criticize-muslim-leaders-because-they-have-trade-relations-or-political-alliance-with-countries-that-oppress-muslims-is-it-wrong-of-me-to-say-that-perhaps-this-can-be/",
    "date": "May 22, 2023 5:13 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: The 5 fard prayers were made fard by Allah in the incident of al-Isra wal-Miraj. And the sunnah prayers are the ones that our Rasool (pbuh) used to pray regularly. I am curious that when and how the witr prayer became wajib.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Witr is wajib only upon the prophet salla Allahu alaihi wa sallam. We don\u2019t have any reference to when it was mandated upon him.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-the-5-fard-prayers-were-made-fard-by-allah-in-the-incident-of-al-isra-wal-miraj-and-the-sunnah-prayers-are-the-ones-that-our-rasool-pbuh-used-to-pray-regularly-i-am-curious-that-when-and/",
    "date": "May 19, 2023 10:34 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: A Muslim woman lives in a Non-Muslim country and in an islamophobic home. Can she make Hijrah, if she is able to do so? She is not married yet.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If there is danger on her Islam or she is unable to practice Islam, she must leave the house and live with other mahrams or friends where it is safe. Making hijrah alone would pose more danger on her than staying in her own country.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-a-muslim-woman-lives-in-a-non-muslim-country-and-in-an-islamophobic-home-can-she-make-hijrah-if-she-is-able-to-do-so-she-is-not-married-yet/",
    "date": "May 17, 2023 5:43 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I am a Pakistani and I am blinded who to follow. Imr*n khan is a great leader. I know protesting is haraam etc. How should I handle this situation. Its hard over here",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It is totally prohibited what people are doing in Pakistan and the demonstrations taking place there! They have divided the country and caused chaos and disruption in the land. Those who encourage such demonstrations won\u2019t rest until their country is torn like Yemen and Sudan!",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Islamic Politics"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-am-a-pakistani-and-i-am-blinded-who-to-follow-imrn-khan-is-a-great-leader-i-know-protesting-is-haraam-etc-how-should-i-handle-this-situation-its-hard-over-here/",
    "date": "May 15, 2023 8:45 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Who falls under the bracket of \u0627\u0647\u0644 when we recite the Dua during morning and evening \u0627\u0644\u0644\u0647\u0645 \u0627\u0646\u064a \u0627\u0633\u0627\u0644\u0643 \u0627\u0644\u0639\u0627\u0641\u064a\u0629. Is it consist of persons spouse,children ,parents and siblings or only husband wife and their children ?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Husband, wife and children.",
    "tags": ["Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-who-falls-under-the-bracket-of-%d8%a7%d9%87%d9%84-when-we-recite-the-dua-during-morning-and-evening-%d8%a7%d9%84%d9%84%d9%87%d9%85-%d8%a7%d9%86%d9%8a-%d8%a7%d8%b3%d8%a7%d9%84%d9%83-%d8%a7/",
    "date": "May 12, 2023 9:20 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If the imam in the masjid says the starting takbir of the prayer and I\u2019m praying the sunnah prayer but I\u2019m in home and also I didn\u2019t hear the imam, would that sunnah prayer be valid (for example in case of Fajr where you pray sunnah and go and see one rakah has gone) because after the takbir no other prayer is valid.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If you heard the iqamah, you should have rushed to join the congregation. But if you did not hear it and was not aware of it, your voluntary prayer is valid.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-the-imam-in-the-masjid-says-the-starting-takbir-of-the-prayer-and-im-praying-the-sunnah-prayer-but-im-in-home-and-also-i-didnt-hear-the-imam-would-that-sunnah-prayer-be-valid-for/",
    "date": "May 10, 2023 10:29 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My brother is oppressing his wife, he doesn\u2019t allow her to go anywhere, he doesn\u2019t allow her to visit her parents or her siblings even when there\u2019s events like marriage or child birth, he only allows her to come with him a a few hours when there\u2019s an even in our house, our mother spoke to him but he aggressively defended himself and said he will never allow her any freedom, what should we do?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Such a brother is arrogant and not following the Sunnah of the prophet salla Allahu alaihi wa sallam and his marriage is bound to be a miserable one or end up in divorce. I am constantly counseling people like him on daily basis and I feel the hardship that their wives are undergoing. Keep on advising him with good manners, wisdom, knowledge, and diplomacy. Plan for the worst and be ready to support the poor wife in her divorce case and custody of the children.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage", "Kind Treatment of Spouses"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-brother-is-oppressing-his-wife-he-doesnt-allow-her-to-go-anywhere-he-doesnt-allow-her-to-visit-her-parents-or-her-siblings-even-when-theres-events-like-marriage-or-child-birth-he/",
    "date": "May 8, 2023 2:59 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I always try to give salam to my husband\u2019s relatives but some of them don\u2019t like it and don\u2019t reply back and it makes me feel stupid so I feel like giving greeting them in an Islamic way. Should I keep giving them salam or just say normal hello?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Keep giving them salam and if they don\u2019t reply, they are sinful and Angels would reply to your salam instead.",
    "tags": [
      "Dealings and Attitudes with In-Laws",
      "Etiquette, Morals and Heart-Softeners"
    ],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-always-try-to-give-salam-to-my-husbands-relatives-but-some-of-them-dont-like-it-and-dont-reply-back-and-it-makes-me-feel-stupid-so-i-feel-like-giving-greeting-th/",
    "date": "May 7, 2023 2:20 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh. My family members before praying recite \u201cI have turned my face in complete devotion to the One Who created the heavens and the earth, and I am not one of the polytheists\u201d and they do this before the starting of first salah they are offering at a particular time. Eg:- Before 2 rakahs of fajr sunnah, before 2 rakahs of zuhr sunnah",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is an innovation if done before takbeer.",
    "tags": ["Innovations", "Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-my-family-members-before-praying-recite-i-have-turned-my-face-in-complete-devotion-to-the-one-who-created-the-heavens-and-the-earth-and-i-am-not-one-of-the-polytheists-an/",
    "date": "May 4, 2023 2:50 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it right for a parent to ask their daughter to leave the house to buy groceries for them, or should that be the job of the male family members. I don\u2019t know if I should obey them and go out or follow the verse of staying in the house.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem if its a safe place and you are dressed properly in an Islamic abaya and behave modestly when outside.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Women clothing"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-right-for-a-parent-to-ask-their-daughter-to-leave-the-house-to-buy-groceries-for-them-or-should-that-be-the-job-of-the-male-family-members-i-dont-know-if-i-should-obey-them/",
    "date": "May 2, 2023 8:52 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My uncle recently died because of liver cancer. It seems to us that he didnt pray almost at all. A few days before his death, he was told to accept that what he did was wrong and to repent, and he did so alhamdulillah. After that he suffered terribly due to brutal pain, thus he didnt start praying during his last days. Is his repentance still valid? Is he considered a martyr?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is in Allah\u2019s hands. We judge with what is apparent and only Allah knows and decides people\u2019s fate. All you can do now is pray for his forgiveness.",
    "tags": ["Funerals", "Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-uncle-recently-died-because-of-liver-cancer-it-seems-to-us-that-he-didnt-pray-almost-at-all-a-few-days-before-his-death-he-was-told-to-accept-that-what-he-did-was-wrong-and-to-repent/",
    "date": "April 29, 2023 12:59 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: We know that after the imam recites al-Fatihah, we recite ourselves but if the imam starts another surah should we continue our recitation of al-Fatihah ?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You can quickly finish it if you have already started reciting it.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-we-know-that-after-the-imam-recites-al-fatihah-we-recite-ourselves-but-if-the-imam-starts-another-surah-should-we-continue-our-recitation-of-al-fatihah/",
    "date": "April 25, 2023 8:20 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: On the laylatul qadar we should read 7 times surah qadar is this authentic?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not authentic and its an innovation.",
    "tags": ["Fasting and Ramadan", "Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-on-the-laylatul-qadar-we-should-read-7-times-surah-qadar-is-this-authentic/",
    "date": "April 18, 2023 3:40 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I have heard that every person has a Jinn who whispers evil thoughts to him/her, influencing them towards evil and distraction in worship. I want to know whether it is permissible to make dua for my Jinn to become a muslim, as I heard the prophet (peace be upon him) narrated that his Jinn became a muslim. So should I make dua for my Jinn to be guided to Islam and stop annoying me?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not permissible as its transgression in dua! This was only exclusive for Prophet salla Allahu alaihi wa sallam.",
    "tags": ["Jinn, Witchcraft, Black Magic and the Evil Eye", "Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-have-heard-that-every-person-has-a-jinn-who-whispers-evil-thoughts-to-him-her-influencing-them-towards-evil-and-distraction-in-worship-i-want-to-know-whether-it-is-permissible-to-make-du/",
    "date": "April 16, 2023 12:28 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is someone sinful for delaying making up missed days of Ramadan, due to a legit reason?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: As long as they make it up before the following Ramadan, they are not sinful.",
    "tags": ["Fasting and Ramadan"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-someone-sinful-for-delaying-making-up-missed-days-of-ramadan-due-to-a-legit-reason/",
    "date": "April 13, 2023 12:04 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If I didn\u2019t cut my nails within the 40 days will my prayer be valid? Or will I be sinned for it?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You\u2019re sinful for delaying to cut them for this long but this has no impact on your prayers.",
    "tags": ["Purity"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-i-didnt-cut-my-nails-within-the-40-days-will-my-prayer-be-valid-or-will-i-be-sinned-for-it/",
    "date": "April 11, 2023 2:53 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: What are the things that attracts jinns? Some say\u2019s that\u00a0staying in dark , having long hair nd applying perfumes attracts the jinns is this correct?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No. Maintain your daily adkhar and you will be protected from every evil with Allah\u2019s Mercy. PROTECTION: You must maintain your 5 daily prayers on time without fail. Fix a time for reciting Qur\u2019an everyday. Maintain your daily adhkar of morning and evening, before going to bed, after every fard prayer, while entering the washroom, while going out of the house, before eating etc and this will act as a shield against everything evil with the Mercy of Allah. You will find these duas in a booklet called \u2018Hisnul Muslim\u2019 or \u2018Fortress of the Muslim.\u2019",
    "tags": ["Jinn, Witchcraft, Black Magic and the Evil Eye"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-what-are-the-things-that-attracts-jinns-some-says-that-staying-in-dark-having-long-hair-nd-applying-perfumes-attracts-the-jinns-is-this-correct/",
    "date": "April 7, 2023 4:28 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If I intend to pray shaf\u2019i 2 rak\u2019ah and then 1 rak\u2019ah witr after it can I change my mind during prayer and make it 3 rak\u2019ah witr? E.g., instead of sitting for the second rak\u2019ah I get up and make the prayer witr. And vice versa, i.e., intending to pray 3 but making it 2 + 1 instead?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-i-intend-to-pray-shafi-2-rakah-and-then-1-rakah-witr-after-it-can-i-change-my-mind-during-prayer-and-make-it-3-rakah-witr-e-g-instead-of-sitting-for-the-second-rakah-i-get-up/",
    "date": "April 5, 2023 4:20 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If I (woman) passed in front of someone while they are praying in a group by mistake, that I wanted to catch up with the prayer, would the one I crossed in front them repeat the prayer? Or what should I do or what should they do?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You invalidated their prayer if you crossed their sujood spot if they were praying alone. They must restart their prayer.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-i-woman-passed-in-front-of-someone-while-they-are-praying-in-a-group-by-mistake-that-i-wanted-to-catch-up-with-the-prayer-would-the-one-i-crossed-in-front-them-repeat-the-prayer-or-w/",
    "date": "April 2, 2023 3:10 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Shaykh, nowadays a new trend has emerged among the Muslim youth where they post their good deeds on social media. Does it amout to Riya?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Yes.",
    "tags": ["Social Media"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-shaykh-nowadays-a-new-trend-has-emerged-among-the-muslim-youth-where-they-post-their-good-deeds-on-social-media-does-it-amout-to-riya/",
    "date": "March 31, 2023 7:03 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it necessary to do wadhu facing the Qibla because in our house the taps\ud83d\udeb0 is not towards the Qibla?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No.",
    "tags": ["Ablution (Wudhu)"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-necessary-to-do-wadhu-facing-the-qibla-because-in-our-house-the-taps%f0%9f%9a%b0-is-not-towards-the-qibla/",
    "date": "March 29, 2023 6:47 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: There is a women I know, who, due to a medical condition, has a constantly leaking bladder. She is under the impression that due to this she cannot pray as she cannot be in wudhu and has not been praying. Is she correct in thinking this or how can we advise her ?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Nobody is exempted from praying, not even the dying person on his death bed!! She must pray on time at all times regardless of her circumstances!",
    "tags": ["Ablution (Wudhu)", "Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-there-is-a-women-i-know-who-due-to-a-medical-condition-has-a-constantly-leaking-bladder-she-is-under-the-impression-that-due-to-this-she-cannot-pray-as-she-cannot-be-in-wudhu-and-has-not/",
    "date": "March 26, 2023 4:25 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: There\u2019s a calendar during Ramadan that specifies what to recite and how many rakaa\u2019a to perform after Taraweeh and before you go to sleep but it is not mandatory. It goes from the first night to the last night. For example it will say \u201cfirst night perform 6 rakaa in each you recite one fatiha, one surah al Qadr and four surah Al Qafirun\u201d.. is this an innovation or is it permissible to perform?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is an innovation.",
    "tags": ["Fasting and Ramadan", "Innovations", "Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-theres-a-calendar-during-ramadan-that-specifies-what-to-recite-and-how-many-rakaaa-to-perform-after-taraweeh-and-before-you-go-to-sleep-but-it-is-not-mandatory-it-goes-fro/",
    "date": "March 24, 2023 9:47 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My cat is not sterilized , so sometimes when I am sleeping he used my hand for mating , and I can see some semen drops on my hand. So will it make me impure for prayers ?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Of course its impure!",
    "tags": ["Purity"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-cat-is-not-sterilized-so-sometimes-when-i-am-sleeping-he-used-my-hand-for-mating-and-i-can-see-some-semen-drops-on-my-hand-so-will-it-make-me-impure-for-prayers/",
    "date": "March 21, 2023 4:42 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I\u2019m revert and got married to Muslim guy with his parents and wali but concealed it from my parents as there was danger of suicide of parents and health as I\u2019m the only child.Now things have become better and I want to get married to my husband infront of parents but not tell them about previous marriage as it might cause severe health issues for them and them cutting ties with me.can we redo nikah",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If your father is a kafir and you have no Muslim guardian, the Muslim judge or the authorized imam of the Islamic center becomes your guardian. If the Muslim judge is the one who married you to your Muslim husband, this is valid and the marriage is correct. You must not renew the marriage contract in front of your disbeliever family as there is no need for that and you can tell that to them directly.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage", "Fiqh of the family"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-im-revert-and-got-married-to-muslim-guy-with-his-parents-and-wali-but-concealed-it-from-my-parents-as-there-was-danger-of-suicide-of-parents-and-health-as-im-the-only-child/",
    "date": "March 19, 2023 5:27 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I have a question regarding Zakat that I was hoping you could help me with. I currently have 300gm of gold, which is above the nisab. I was wondering if it is possible for me to distribute or gift this gold to my children who are aged 5, 11, and 17",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It\u2019s your choice, but if you gift them then it must be for real and not to get away from paying zakat! It would belong to them and not you anymore.",
    "tags": ["Zakat"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-have-a-question-regarding-zakat-that-i-was-hoping-you-could-help-me-with-i-currently-have-300gm-of-gold-which-is-above-the-nisab-i-was-wondering-if-it-is-possible-for-me-to-distribute-o/",
    "date": "March 18, 2023 3:51 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I said \u201cwallahi this person was the one who burnt the plastic bowl\u201d and then another person said no it was this one, the one I claimed also agreed with her and it felt more accurate to me but I still have doubt, should I fast 3 days as an expiation?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Oaths that must be expiated are oaths over things in the future such as wallahi I will do this or I won\u2019t do that. Oaths over things in the past don\u2019t require expiation. If a person lied on purpose, this is sinful and known as \u201cdipping\u201d oath that dips the person in hell.",
    "tags": ["Oaths"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-said-wallahi-this-person-was-the-one-who-burnt-the-plastic-bowl-and-then-another-person-said-no-it-was-this-one-the-one-i-claimed-also-agreed-with-her-and-it-felt-more-a/",
    "date": "March 16, 2023 4:07 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Can a man divorce his wife without paying the full meher that was decided upon?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: He must give her the mahr as it\u2019s a debt on him.",
    "tags": ["Divorce", "Dowry"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-can-a-man-divorce-his-wife-without-paying-the-full-meher-that-was-decided-upon/",
    "date": "March 13, 2023 11:36 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it okay to feel like I\u2019ll be happy and content in marrying someone,according to his deen and akhlaq, even after getting engaged to someone else?both of us are praying to Allah& waiting for some miracle bcs we like eachother for Allah\u2019s sake alone and want to get married. as now cancelling an engagement without any prop reason would cost family\u2019s respect. what should be done in this scenario",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You shouldn\u2019t marry someone you don\u2019t want to marry him just because you fear losing respect for your family! If that person is a suitable suitor and a practicing Muslim with a good salary and comes from a good family, he is a bargain that you must not lose! The one you love is just a mirage and many such affairs were bound to fail after marriage because he didn\u2019t turn to be as he claimed. Be more realistic and weigh the pros and cons. If you can\u2019t accept the one you are engaged to at all, break the engagement but also forget all about the one you have feelings for as your father will never accept him and he will never marry you.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-okay-to-feel-like-ill-be-happy-and-content-in-marrying-someoneaccording-to-his-deen-and-akhlaq-even-after-getting-engaged-to-someone-elseboth-of-us-are-praying-to-allah-wa/",
    "date": "March 13, 2023 12:50 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: We know that Allah has veil. Is the veil, a separate being/thing from Allah like Allah\u2019s other creations like arsh, kursi etc or it is also Allah\u2019s attribute? Can you tell in details.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It is not one of Allah\u2019s attributes. It is one of Allah\u2019s creations which the prophet salla Allahu alaihi wa sallam had seen.",
    "tags": ["Names and Attributes of Allaah"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-we-know-that-allah-has-veil-is-the-veil-a-separate-being-thing-from-allah-like-allahs-other-creations-like-arsh-kursi-etc-or-it-is-also-allahs-attribute-can-you-tell-in-details/",
    "date": "March 11, 2023 1:10 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is anal sex and blow job HARAM for married couples ? And what if my wife doesn\u2019t want to do it .",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Anal sex is totally prohibited and a major sin & whoever does it is cursed by Allah.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-anal-sex-and-blow-job-haram-for-married-couples-and-what-if-my-wife-doesnt-want-to-do-it/",
    "date": "March 8, 2023 4:13 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I made long dua in the 2nd sujood of the first rakah of Isha and joined the imam while he is halfway through fatiha in the 2nd rakah, is there anything wrong?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Yes, you are wrong in not following the imam and going against the prophet\u2019s instructions to immediately follow the imam and not delay.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-made-long-dua-in-the-2nd-sujood-of-the-first-rakah-of-isha-and-joined-the-imam-while-he-is-halfway-through-fatiha-in-the-2nd-rakah-is-there-anything-wrong/",
    "date": "March 7, 2023 2:35 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: A scenario: once/twice someone delayed his Dhuhr prayer for reasons other than forgetfulness/sleep, takes wudu\u2019 & starts praying a short time before \u2018Asr. Towards the end of the prayer, he passes wind. If he were to take wudu\u2019 again to repeat prayer, \u2018Asr would be called. What should he do??",
    "answer": "ANSWER: He must immediately renew his wudu and pray even if the time has passed since the first time he started praying was in the allocated time.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-a-scenario-once-twice-someone-delayed-his-dhuhr-prayer-for-reasons-other-than-forgetfulness-sleep-takes-wudu-starts-praying-a-short-time-before-asr-towards-the-end-of-the-prayer-he/",
    "date": "March 5, 2023 5:41 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Our dad passed away few years ago. Im only son and eldest sibling. 1 sister married, 1 unmarried. They dont do hijab from non mehrams and Free mix. Sisters husband doesnt say anything to his wife (my sis). I tell both to wear hijab, especially unmarried sis. They still dont listen and do what they please. Will our deceased dad and myself be held accountable for them not doing hijab?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If your father didn\u2019t order them when he was alive, he will be accountable. You are responsible to order your unmarried sister to abide by the Islamic laws but the problem is that in today\u2019s times, you don\u2019t have any authority over her especially in kafir countries. You should try your best to instead make her love Allah and Islam by giving her fair preaching and wise dawah without shoving it down her throat and this needs a lot of knowledge and diplomacy.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of the family", "Women clothing"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-our-dad-passed-away-few-years-ago-im-only-son-and-eldest-sibling-1-sister-married-1-unmarried-they-dont-do-hijab-from-non-mehrams-and-free-mix-sisters-husband-doesnt-say-anything-to-his/",
    "date": "March 2, 2023 7:45 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it ok if I recite Surah baqrah outside the house for example when I am at working during my break or if I\u2019m at a doctor appointment and waiting to be called or if I am traveling , will it count as reciting at home ?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No. It should be recited at home to be counted.",
    "tags": ["Jinn, Witchcraft, Black Magic and the Evil Eye", "Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-ok-if-i-recite-surah-baqrah-outside-the-house-for-example-when-i-am-at-working-during-my-break-or-if-im-at-a-doctor-appointment-and-waiting-to-be-called-or-if-i-am-traveling/",
    "date": "March 1, 2023 2:05 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My sisters husband is a bank principal officer earning handsome salary from a haram commercial bank. He is going to buy a flat in city by 0% interest rate which will be given him from his bank. The amount will be cut from his monthly salary as installment. Now will it be halal or permissible for my sister and her child\u2019s to live in that flat?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: His income is haram due to the nature of his job. However, it is haram for him alone and he will be punished for it all. His family can live there and enjoy it as it is halal for them.",
    "tags": ["Loans", "Riba"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-sisters-husband-is-a-bank-principal-officer-earning-handsome-salary-from-a-haram-commercial-bank-he-is-going-to-buy-a-flat-in-city-by-0-interest-rate-which-will-be-given-him-from-his-ban/",
    "date": "February 27, 2023 1:37 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh,can we make any dua during rain in our own words and language,like \u201cOh Allah bless my parents with strong iman health and happiness\u201d or does it have to be the duas proven in Sunnah only?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in making your own dua.",
    "tags": ["Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikhcan-we-make-any-dua-during-rain-in-our-own-words-and-languagelike-oh-allah-bless-my-parents-with-strong-iman-health-and-happiness-or-does-it-have-to-be-the-duas-proven-in-sunnah/",
    "date": "February 25, 2023 10:39 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Well, please tell me if parents are giving trouble, burden, cursing, obscenities, preferring son, Being a girl, spending money is considered a waste and even denying basic rights like clothes, food, education and even disease. Even if the treatment is not done, then will not Allah punish those parents a lot? Please tell me?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: They are accountable to Allah for not taking care of their children or being fair with them and will be punished for that.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of the family"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-well-please-tell-me-if-parents-are-giving-trouble-burden-cursing-obscenities-preferring-son-being-a-girl-spending-money-is-considered-a-waste-and-even-denying-basic-rights-like-clothe/",
    "date": "February 22, 2023 4:48 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh is that haram to keep a friendship who makes us closer to our Deen (surely not with the opposite gender) even if our parents don\u2019t want us to have such friendships because they\u2019re scared if we get brainwashed? If we keep our friendship, will we be disobeying our parents?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If this individual is extreme and not properly following the way of the prophet salla Allahu alaihi wa sallam, you must not befriend him and you must obey your parents. But if he is righteous and practicing has good akhlaq and follows the sunnah with wisdom and according to the understanding of the 3 favorite generations, you must not listen to your parents in this regards.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of the family"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-is-that-haram-to-keep-a-friendship-who-makes-us-closer-to-our-deen-surely-not-with-the-opposite-gender-even-if-our-parents-dont-want-us-to-have-such-friendships-because-theyre-s/",
    "date": "February 20, 2023 7:50 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: There is hadith, whoever misses 3 jumuah, Allah will seal his heart. What is the meaning? Missing 3 jumuah with khutba or just the 2 rakah prayer itself! If WITH khutba then what if one arrives 15/20 mins late? Please clarify",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It\u2019s about intentionally missing the 2 rakahs of Friday prayer.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-there-is-hadith-whoever-misses-3-jumuah-allah-will-seal-his-heart-what-is-the-meaning-missing-3-jumuah-with-khutba-or-just-the-2-rakah-prayer-itself-if-with-khutba-then-what-if-one-arri/",
    "date": "February 17, 2023 1:13 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My wife disobeyed me. I have asked her to go get some stuff from the grocery store and make me something I wanted. And she said, \u201cYou go do the groceries, and I will make you it.\u201d Is her not wanting to go the grocery store a disobedience?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Of course not! A real man doesn\u2019t ask his wife to go out to buy things!",
    "tags": ["Kind Treatment of Spouses"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-wife-disobeyed-me-i-have-asked-her-to-go-get-some-stuff-from-the-grocery-store-and-make-me-something-i-wanted-and-she-said-you-go-do-the-groceries-and-i-will-make-you-it-is-her-n/",
    "date": "February 14, 2023 9:14 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it true that if we pray in congregation imam will carry the burden for our mistakes ?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Correct, as long as you have joined him from the beginning.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-true-that-if-we-pray-in-congregation-imam-will-carry-the-burden-for-our-mistakes/",
    "date": "February 10, 2023 7:10 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: In our country as far as I know there is only shia masjid. Is it permissible to skip jummah prayer and do it alone?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You must do your due diligence and find out if there are any sunni masjid in your city and if its there, you must pray your Friday there, even if its far off. If there are no sunni masjids at all, not even one then you can gather other sunni brothers and make Friday. If this is not possible at all then you can pray dhuhr.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-in-our-country-as-far-as-i-know-there-is-only-shia-masjid-is-it-permissible-to-skip-jummah-prayer-and-do-it-alone/",
    "date": "February 8, 2023 6:17 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh, Cattle Owners are told to bring their animals to nearest veterinaries to pierce Ear Tags into their ears for identification with a registration number.. It\u2019s happening worldwide. Does that make our animals ineligible for sacrifices as there\u2019s a hole in their ears?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem as this is not a defect.",
    "tags": ["Slaughtering"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-cattle-owners-are-told-to-bring-their-animals-to-nearest-veterinaries-to-pierce-ear-tags-into-their-ears-for-identification-with-a-registration-number-its-happening-worldwide-do/",
    "date": "February 7, 2023 11:09 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Been married to my husband for 5 years and have 1 small daughter. In laws keep on telling vulgar things about my family. They never can accept my husband having good relation with them. My mother in law is the main person to use my father in law as a weapon to always trigger my husband. Son has stopped contact with them for our peace orelse they just make everything worse. What should I do ?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: He is sinful for not contacting them. He should go and be dutiful and respectful to them but must not reply to their abuse or defend you or your family. Let them talk as if they are crazy talking to themselves without replying to them.",
    "tags": ["Dealings and Attitudes with In-Laws", "Fiqh of the family"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-been-married-to-my-husband-for-5-years-and-have-1-small-daughter-in-laws-keep-on-telling-vulgar-things-about-my-family-they-never-can-accept-my-husband-having-good-relation-with-them-my-m/",
    "date": "February 6, 2023 1:27 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh if a person steals food and eats will what he/she eats be considered haram and as a result their dua will not be accepted?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Yes.",
    "tags": ["Character and Morals"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-if-a-person-steals-food-and-eats-will-what-he-she-eats-be-considered-haram-and-as-a-result-their-dua-will-not-be-accepted/",
    "date": "February 4, 2023 1:13 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Hadith states,among signs of qiyama,\u201dslave gives birth to her master\u201d. What\u2019s the meaning? When there was slavery, literally slave used to give birth to her master\u2019s child but what the meaning here?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: There are several views among the scholars as to what this means. The view favored by Ibn Hajar is that there will be widespread disobedience among children, so that a child will treat his mother as a master treats his slave woman, with negligence and insults.",
    "tags": ["Belief in the Last Day and the Signs of the Hour"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-hadith-statesamong-signs-of-qiyamaslave-gives-birth-to-her-master-whats-the-meaning-when-there-was-slavery-literally-slave-used-to-give-birth-to-her-masters-child-but-what-the-m/",
    "date": "February 1, 2023 9:23 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If someone don\u2019t sin infront of someone religious, people degrade him by saying u fear him but u don\u2019t fear Allah and same with secret Sinning and openly Sinning though, openly Sinning is more bad ,PlZZ advise how should we advise ourselves &these people,",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not true! One is ashamed of sinning in front of others as we are ordered to conceal our sins in front of people. As for sinning between us and allah, this is human weakness and May Allah forgive our shortcomings.",
    "tags": ["Sins"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-someone-dont-sin-infront-of-someone-religious-people-degrade-him-by-saying-u-fear-him-but-u-dont-fear-allah-and-same-with-secret-sinning-and-openly-sinning-though-openly-sinning-is/",
    "date": "January 30, 2023 7:26 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I\u2019ll go for Umrah from Bangladesh inshaAllah We\u2019ll wear ihram clothes with the niyyah of Umrah before boarding the airplane because Miqaat will be midway on the plane. Now if I want to take a bath after arriving at the hotel (Jeddah), can I take off the Ihram clothes, take a bath and put on the Ihram clothes again?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in this whatsoever.",
    "tags": ["Hajj and Umrah"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-ill-go-for-umrah-from-bangladesh-inshaallah-well-wear-ihram-clothes-with-the-niyyah-of-umrah-before-boarding-the-airplane-because-miqaat-will-be-midway-on-the-plane-now-if-i-want-to-tak/",
    "date": "January 27, 2023 10:06 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Can we pray with a garments or praying mat that is stained with food or normal dirt",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem as long as it doesn\u2019t have any impurity on it.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-can-we-pray-with-a-garments-or-praying-mat-that-is-stained-with-food-or-normal-dirt/",
    "date": "January 25, 2023 9:14 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is touching someone with lust or molest someone a major or minor sin?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: A major sin.",
    "tags": ["Sins"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-touching-someone-with-lust-or-molest-someone-a-major-or-minor-sin/",
    "date": "January 23, 2023 8:26 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I came to know that it is arrogance to consider myself better than others. But how can I think myself same or below them who are smoking in front of me, watching haram videos, do free mixing? And when they do so what should my mind think of that? Please some advice\u2026..",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Don\u2019t compare yourself to them and don\u2019t think of yourself to be better or worse as this is in Allah\u2019s Hands. Detest their sins but don\u2019t see yourself better than them.",
    "tags": ["Character and Morals", "Etiquette, Morals and Heart-Softeners"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-came-to-know-that-it-is-arrogance-to-consider-myself-better-than-others-but-how-can-i-think-myself-same-or-below-them-who-are-smoking-in-front-of-me-watching-haram-videos-do-free-mixing/",
    "date": "January 19, 2023 9:12 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it true that Rasool Allah Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam did not eat meat,fish and bread if had milk before ?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not true nor authentic.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-true-that-rasool-allah-sallallahu-alaihi-wasallam-did-not-eat-meatfish-and-bread-if-had-milk-before/",
    "date": "January 16, 2023 5:07 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My question is that is the prayer of a smoker not accepted for forty days like that of a person drinking alcohol.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Smoking is prohibited but it won\u2019t render one\u2019s prayers unaccepted as it is not intoxicating like wine and drugs.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-question-is-that-is-the-prayer-of-a-smoker-not-accepted-for-forty-days-like-that-of-a-person-drinking-alcohol/",
    "date": "January 13, 2023 3:13 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: We know that if someone make wudu and sleep on his right side and say \u201cAllahumma aslamtu nafsi ilaika, wa wajjahtu wajhi ilaika, wa fawwadtu amri ilaika, and the rest\u201d then If he dies he will die on Islam.My question is,When someone make wudu and after saying the dua by lying on his right, Can he sleep on his back as he sometimes can\u2019t sleep on his right.Will he have the reward?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem.",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-we-know-that-if-someone-make-wudu-and-sleep-on-his-right-side-and-say-allahumma-aslamtu-nafsi-ilaika-wa-wajjahtu-wajhi-ilaika-wa-fawwadtu-amri-ilaika-and-the-rest-then-if-he-dies-he-w/",
    "date": "January 10, 2023 4:04 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Does making dua for the forgiveness of all Muslim and Muslimats give us around two billion good deeds?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is not true.",
    "tags": ["Innovations", "Supplications"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-does-making-dua-for-the-forgiveness-of-all-muslim-and-muslimats-give-us-around-two-billion-good-deeds/",
    "date": "January 8, 2023 9:40 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: According to Islam new day(next day) starts after maghrib. So if for eg today is Thursday and so after Thursday\u2019s maghrib, Friday has started so does it mean that we can recite surah ka\u2019af after maghrib on a thursday ?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No. You should recite it from fajr of Friday until maghrib of Friday as the reward is in reciting it during the day time.",
    "tags": ["Purity", "Reading/Reciting the Quran"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-according-to-islam-new-daynext-day-starts-after-maghrib-so-if-for-eg-today-is-thursday-and-so-after-thursdays-maghrib-friday-has-started-so-does-it-mean-that-we-can-recite-surah/",
    "date": "January 6, 2023 3:57 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh there is soil in the vicinity of Pakistan border which is claimed to be sacred and a cure for skin diseases but grave worship is very common there. Can we bring that soil by ourselves with the intention that all the land belongs to Almighty Allah.",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is totally prohibited as it is a form of shirk! There is no scientific proof to back such claims and hence, it is shirk.",
    "tags": ["Innovations", "Shirk and its different forms"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-there-is-soil-in-the-vicinity-of-pakistan-border-which-is-claimed-to-be-sacred-and-a-cure-for-skin-diseases-but-grave-worship-is-very-common-there-can-we-bring-that-soil-by-ourselves/",
    "date": "January 4, 2023 4:24 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: There are some videos on YouTube which shows the family background of prophet muhammad sallallahu alaiwasalm (in cartoon) and it shows the faces of the sahaba and all others except Prophet muhammad sallallahu alaiwasalm\u2026so is this permissible to watch such videos",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No, this is not permissible at all!",
    "tags": ["Halal/Haram Matters", "Sports, Entertainment and Music"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-there-are-some-videos-on-youtube-which-shows-the-family-background-of-prophet-muhammad-sallallahu-alaiwasalm-in-cartoon-and-it-shows-the-faces-of-the-sahaba-and-all-others-except-prophet-m/",
    "date": "January 2, 2023 3:58 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My question is that when praying sunnah prayers is it a must to read another surah after surah fatiha or surah fatiha is sufficent?? For eg in isha prayer last 3rd and 4th rakaah only surah fatiha is read\u2026",
    "answer": "ANSWER: It\u2019s not mandatory to recite another surah after fateha even during fard prayers though it is a highly recommended sunnah in the 1st and 2nd rakah.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-question-is-that-when-praying-sunnah-prayers-is-it-a-must-to-read-another-surah-after-surah-fatiha-or-surah-fatiha-is-sufficent-for-eg-in-isha-prayer-last-3rd-and-4th-rakaah-only-surah/",
    "date": "January 1, 2023 2:29 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: I aim for the generous reward mentioned for Friday prayer by completing the following: Doing ghusl, cleansing oneself, going to the mosque early, walking to the mosque and not riding, sitting close to the Imam, listening attentively to the khutbah and not fidgeting. Do I also have to walk back home after the prayer to attain this reward, or is it ok to get a ride back?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem in taking a ride back. However, if you walk, you are still rewarded for every step you make.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-i-aim-for-the-generous-reward-mentioned-for-friday-prayer-by-completing-the-following-doing-ghusl-cleansing-oneself-going-to-the-mosque-early-walking-to-the-mosque-and-not-riding-sitti/",
    "date": "December 30, 2022 3:55 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Sheikh.. I want to ask what should one do when his/her parents always keep comparing them to other children or even compare a girl child with a boy cause this leads to such a toxic heartbreak..?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: A righteous child is not concerned by such remarks because he is doing what he is doing for the sake of Allah and he anticipates the reward from Him alone. He pardons his parents due to their ignorance and he continues to give them unconditional love even if they are ungrateful. He doesn\u2019t show them any sign or resentment or disappointment but rather remains dutiful, obedient and respectful throughout the whole time. His reward is with Allah.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of the family", "Psychological Problems"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-sheikh-i-want-to-ask-what-should-one-do-when-his-her-parents-always-keep-comparing-them-to-other-children-or-even-compare-a-girl-child-with-a-boy-cause-this-leads-to-such-a-toxic-heartbrea/",
    "date": "December 28, 2022 2:45 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: If a father liked a guy for her daughter and her daughter too willing to marry him without having any problem and her father gave green light,then is it mandatory for her to obey her mother as she did not like the groom for her daughter\u2026.?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No! What counts is her own father\u2019s approval and her consent. Her mother\u2019s approval doesn\u2019t matter.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage", "Marriage Contract"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-if-a-father-liked-a-guy-for-her-daughter-and-her-daughter-too-willing-to-marry-him-without-having-any-problem-and-her-father-gave-green-lightthen-is-it-mandatory-for-her-to-obey-her-mother/",
    "date": "December 26, 2022 2:48 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Can a person wear gloves and hold the Quran without being pure?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: No problem. However, if they are junoob (major sexual impurity), its not permissible to recite the Quran.",
    "tags": ["Purity", "Reading/Reciting the Quran"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-can-a-person-wear-gloves-and-hold-the-quran-without-being-pure/",
    "date": "December 24, 2022 3:48 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it haram for parents to hide the fact that their son is autistic while looking for a bride for him?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: This is lying and cheating her! How would they feel if the woman hid from them that she has herpes or HIV+?",
    "tags": ["Character and Morals", "Fiqh of Marriage"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-haram-for-parents-to-hide-the-fact-that-their-son-is-autistic-while-looking-for-a-bride-for-him/",
    "date": "December 22, 2022 4:21 am"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: My husband cheated on me with multiple people. Some men. I asked what I did wrong to cause this so that I can make corrections. He said it was not me. I want to be a good wife but I feel anger many times and I am now in suffering insomnia at night from my inability to stop thinking of it. What should I do to stop this thinking?",
    "answer": "ANSWER: If he has stoped cheating on you and now he is faithful, you should stop thinking about the past and move on with your life, trying to be a good wife and praying to Allah that He makes your marriage a blessed and happy one. But if he is still cheating on you and has not stopped, you shouldn\u2019t stay married to such a person as he is not a good husband and you don\u2019t want to end up suffering from STD.",
    "tags": ["Fiqh of Marriage"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-my-husband-cheated-on-me-with-multiple-people-some-men-i-asked-what-i-did-wrong-to-cause-this-so-that-i-can-make-corrections-he-said-it-was-not-me-i-want-to-be-a-good-wife-but-i-feel-an/",
    "date": "December 20, 2022 9:42 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: Is it possible for a person to give his own self evil eye? By admiring or being amazed by something that he has, and not saying mashaaAllah laa quuwata illaa billah",
    "answer": "ANSWER: Yes, this is possible.",
    "tags": ["Jinn, Witchcraft, Black Magic and the Evil Eye"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-is-it-possible-for-a-person-to-give-his-own-self-evil-eye-by-admiring-or-being-amazed-by-something-that-he-has-and-not-saying-mashaaallah-laa-quuwata-illaa-billah/",
    "date": "December 18, 2022 6:43 pm"
  },
  {
    "question": "QUESTION: How to pray Sunnah arawatib while traveling. (In case if you receive this question twice I sent the first time it\u2019s say failed to send. I have no intention of breaking the rules sir).",
    "answer": "ANSWER: You should not pray the Sunnah of dhuhr, Maghrib and Isha as Prophet salla Allahu Alaihi wa Sallam used to skip these while traveling. Other than that, you can pray as many voluntary prayers as you want, including 2 Sunnah before Fajr and Witr as Prophet salla Allahu Alaihi wa Sallam never missed these even while traveling.",
    "tags": ["Prayer"],
    "author": "assim-al-hakeem",
    "url": "question-how-to-pray-sunnah-arawatib-while-traveling-in-case-if-you-receive-this-question-twice-i-sent-the-first-time-its-say-failed-to-send-i-have-no-intention-of-breaking-the-rules-sir/",
    "date": "December 16, 2022 1:33 am"
  }
]
